郑重声明:本作品之片源、字幕均来自互联网，版权归原电影公司所有。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业盈利用途，否则一切后果由该组织或个人承担！制作者不承担任何法律及连带责任！请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
蓝精灵 2
片源
天天美剧
统筹
Roy
ABBY
翻译
WOOSA Wilsonju
自心 Mr.Gao
Cheer Saber
仑仔 大伟神
卟哒哒 涤墨墨
塔塔 阿狸
Roy♥ABBY
校对
Mr.Gao 卟哒哒
阿狸 Saber
Roy♥ABBY
特效 后期
封装 压制
阿狸 ABBY
HIMYM字幕组
倾情奉献
蓝精灵魔法时间
Time to smurf some magic.
我来瞧瞧
Let's see.
你在这啊
There you are.
含羞草花粉
Mimosa pollen.
没错 来点虎皮百合
Yes, tiger lily
将魔法与蓝色赋予她的精华
to make her essence magical and blue.
如果这个咒语真的能起作用的话
Unless this spell be all for naught,
最后一步 一个美好的愿望
the final thing, one hopeful thought.
很久很久以前 在蓝精灵村
Once upon a time, in Smurf Village,
欢乐的蓝精灵们过着幸福的生活
happy Smurfs were going about their happy lives
全然不知就在村子的不远处
completely unaware that not too far away,
有一个坏巫师格格巫
the evil wizard Gargamel
正在酝酿一个邪恶的计划
was concocting a diabolical plan.
嘿
Hey.
Hey!
滑滑 你抢了旁白念念的戏
Smooth, you're upstaging the narrator.
哟 音量下调一格好了 蓝兄弟们
Yo, take it down a notch, my blues brothers.
-好吧 好的  -谢了 紧接着...
-All right. All right. -Thank you. Anyway...
格格巫说道
So Gargamel said,
我要造一个属于自己的秘密武器
"I am making my own irresistible creation,
蓝妹妹
The Smurfette,
让她潜入村子 然后出卖所有蓝精灵
to infiltrate their village and betray the Smurfs."
哇哦
Wow.
她看起来好吓人啊
Not a good look on her.
-她是个科学怪精灵吗  -没错
-She's a Frankensmurf? -Yes.
原词Frankenstein 科学怪人
她淘气的天性搞得蓝精灵村鸡飞狗跳
And her naughty nature took Smurf Village by storm.
她甚至用大水淹掉了村子
She even flooded our village.
蓝精灵们希望她消失
The Smurfs wanted her gone,
但即使她是格格巫造出来的
but even though she was Gargamel's creation,
爸爸却看出了她善良的一面
Papa saw the good in her.
用爱 善良 一次改头换面
With love, kindness, a complete makeover,
还有一个神秘的魔法配方
and a secret magic formula,
爸爸把她变成了一个真正的蓝精灵
he turned her into a true-blue Smurf,
我们亲爱的蓝妹妹就是这样来的
and that is how our darling Smurfette came to be.
-嗨  -我的亲娘唉
-Hi. -Holy moly.
嗨 蓝妹妹
Hi, Smurfette.
好羡慕她的头发
I wish I had that hair.
-跳得漂亮 蓝妹妹  -太不可思议了
-Nice dive, Smurfette. -That was amazing.
哇 臭显摆
Wow. Show-off.
漂亮
Pretty!
-太美了  -漂亮的抱膝转体
-That was so purty. -Nice tuck and roll.
-嗨  -就像一条美人鱼
-Hi! -Like a beautiful mermaid.
等等 她头发怎么还是干的
Wait, how is her hair still dry?
噢 不
Oh, no.
怎么...
What...
愚蠢又天真的蓝精灵啊
Stupid, trusting Smurfs.
现在都是我的了
You're mine now.
-她还活着  -快到蓝精灵山去
-It's alive! -Smurf for the hills!
别杀旁白君啊
Don't kill the narrator!
我们的世界要完蛋了
The world as we know it is over!
她有龙之魔杖
She's got a Dragon Wand.
别弄坏我的纸杯蛋糕
Don't hurt my cupcake!
小心啊
Look out!
真棒 我漂亮的小家伙
Yes! My beautiful creation.
你真是爸爸的好女儿
You truly are daddy's little girl.
不...
No...
蓝妹妹 你还好吗
Smurfette, are you okay?
哦 爸爸
Oh, Papa.
没事 乖啦 一切都会好起来的
There, there. Everything's going to be fine.
又做那个噩梦了吗
Having that nightmare again?
爸爸 每年一到我过生日的时候
Papa, every year on my birthday,
我就会做相同的恶梦 梦到我是怎么来的
I have these horrible dreams about where I come from,
这让我怀疑自己 到底是谁
and it makes me wonder who I really am.
然后每年我都会提醒你
And every year, I remind you,
你来自哪里并不重要
it doesn't matter where you came from.
重要的是你想成为什么样的人
What matters is who you choose to be.
真的吗
Really?
别太在意我这个老人家的话
Don't take this old Smurf's word for it.
自己去外面看看吧
Go out there and see for yourself.
你就是属于这里的
This is where you belong.
你是属于格格巫的
You belong to Gargamel.
"你是属于格格巫的" 快说
"You belong to Gargamel." Say it.
"你是属于格格巫的"
"You belong to Gargamel."
是我
I' I
那好吧 算了 先生 你是一只傻癞蛤蟆
You know what? Never mind, sir. You're a dim-witted toad.
"你是一只傻癞蛤蟆吗 先生"
"You're a dim-witted toad, sir?"
不 实际上 你才是
No, actually, you are!
看吧
There.
前无古人后无来者的创新大师格格巫
Yet another groundbreaking feat of illusion
又为全世界观众呈现了一场超乎想象的幻觉盛宴
from the most innovative conjurer the world has ever seen.
格格巫狂热现象
Gargamania,
这场魔法轰动席卷了整个国家
the magical sensation that has captivated
从纽约一直到拉斯维加斯
the nation from New York to Las Vegas,
下一站坐标光明之城 法国巴黎
is now taking on the City of Light, Paris, France.
自从在纽约意外被发现后 这位神秘的大师一炮而红
This master mysterio has gone from unknown to unstoppable
当年名不见经传的他 如今已名声大振
after a surprise discovery in New York.
哟 给我滚远点 怪胎
Yo, get out of the road, freak!
胆子真肥啊 居然敢叫我"哟"
How dare you? How dare you call me "Yo"?
哦 不 把我的车放下来
Hey, no, put my car down.
哟 在上面感觉如何啊
Yo, how do you like it up there?
白痴
Moron.
从纽约的街头表演者到如今在欧洲炙手可热
From New York street performer to the new toast of Europe,
他是史上唯一一个在著名的巴黎歌剧院表演的魔术师
the only magician ever to play the famed Paris Opera House.
稍后内容更精彩哦
Stay tuned.
噢 我的天 咱能不能就安安静静的坐一次马车
Oh, dear gods, can we please just have one quiet carriage ride
你别再指责我滥用蓝精灵精华了 要被你折磨死了
without you tormenting me about using up all the Smurf essence?
在纽约王国的时候
I extracted all I could
我拼了老命提取蓝爸爸的精华
from Papa Smurf in the kingdom of New York.
倒说说你提取了多少啊
How much essence did you extract?
你说我滥用吗
I'm squandering it?
你在说什么鬼话
What are you talking about?
我必须把那个人变成巨型癞蛤蟆
I had to turn that man into a giant toad.
魔术表演就要这样 不是吗
It's a magic show, isn't it?
因为如果没有蓝精华 我就不能...
Because without Smurf essence, I can't...
我跟你讨论这个干嘛 你一点魔法都没有
Why am I even discussing this with you? You don't have any magic!
把这句话贴到你的Facebook主页上舔去吧
Stick that on your Facebook page and lick it.
赞吧 赞吧 管他呢
Like it. Like it. Whatever.
不过
Besides,
我还是有足够的精华
I still have plenty enough essence
用来开展我那可爱的邪恶计划
left to carry out my delightfully diabolical plan.
现在 我亲爱的民众们在召唤我了
Now, my adoring public desires me.
你们好
Hello!
你们好 卑微的小马屁精们
Hello, my lowly little bootlicks.
是的 你们都要拜倒在我的脚下
Yes, you must all worship me.
是的
Yes.
还有你 我满身跳蚤毛绒小包包
Even you, my flea-bitten little fur bag.
万岁 伟大而强大的...
All hail the great and powerful...
阿兹猫...阿兹猫...住手
Azrael... Azrael... Stop it.
打开 打开
Open it! Open it!
过来 阿兹猫 快点
Come, Azrael. Hurry up.
你好啊 帅哥
Hello, handsome.
看啊 有个礼物
Look, a present.
肯定是仰慕者送来的
No doubt from a worshipping admirer.
是给你的啊
It's for you.
你才不可能比我受欢迎
You are not more popular than I am.
一个绿色的小点
A little green dot?
为什么你总是收到小绿点呢
Why do you get all the little green dots?
抓住它 抓住它
Get it, get it.
爸爸一定会喜欢这个的
Father's going to love this.
-汉库斯想玩  -嘿
-Hackus want to play. -Hey!
让汉库斯跟猫咪玩玩
Let Hackus play with the kitty.
掩护我
Cover me.
我要上了
I'm going in.
你好 猫咪
Hello, kitty.
维可西
Vexy!
好了 我的小淘气精灵
All right, my little Naughties.
耶
Yeah!
汉库斯伸出援手
Hackus to the rescue!
噢耶
Booyah!
干得漂亮 汉库斯
Good save, Hackus.
拉 快拉
Pull, pull!
汉库斯捕猫 捕到一只大家伙
Hackus cat-fishing. Caught a big one.
第12回合 淘气精灵赢
And round 12 goes to the Naughties.
说得好 我的傻兄弟
Well said, my dim brother.
显而易见 这不是礼物 阿兹猫
Apparently, it wasn't a gift, Azrael.
这是个陷阱
It was a trap.
-真好玩 我的小淘气精灵  -嘿
-Very amusing, my little Naughties. -Hey!
我们让你开心了吗 爸爸
Did we please you, Father?
不 不 你没有
No, no, you didn't.
你知道什么会让我开心吗
You know what would please me,
维可西 如果你像真正的蓝精灵一样也是蓝色的
Vexy, if you were blue like real Smurfs,
那么你们的精华就能赋予我真实的魔力
then your essence would endow
就像一个真正的蓝精灵那样
me with real magic like that of a true-blue Smurf.
那样我才兴奋呢
That would excite me.
相反 你们俩都只是让人失望透顶的试验品罢了
Instead, you're both just deeply disappointing experiments.
试验品吗
Experiment?
就跟我那叛徒蓝妹妹一样
Like my traitor Smurfette.
横幅要挂那边去 谢谢啦
The banner goes over there, please.
非常感谢 还有那个大丽花真不错
Thank you, and I love the pinnata.
-这样如何 勇勇  -再低一点点 厌厌
-How's that, Gutsy?  -A little lower, Grouchy.
我想要一棍子把他打进蓝精灵浆果堆
I want to be able to whack him right in the smurf berries.
嗨 厌厌 嗨 勇勇
Hey, Grouchy. Hey, Gutsy.
好棒的蛋糕啊 蓝妹妹一定会爱死这个派对的
What a cake! Smurfette's gonna love this party!
喂 哪个蓝家伙在蓝妹妹的生日蛋糕上啃了一口啊
Hey, who smurfed a bite out of Smurfette's birthday cake?
-不是我  -真的吗  -我不知道
-Not me. -Realy. -I don't know.
-贪贪  -怎么 你们为什么都盯着我看
-Greedy? -What? Why you all looking at me?
嗨 聪聪 这是我为蓝妹妹惊喜派对准备的礼物
Hey, Brainy, here's my present for Smurfette's surprise party.
来吧 乐乐 你真的认为我
Come on, Jokey, do you really think that I,
作为全村最聪明的蓝精灵
the smartest Smurf in the village,
-会被你这种半吊子智商的人糊弄住吗  -没错
-would fall for your sophomoric gag? -Yep.
把卡片给我拿过来
Just give me the card.
竟然被一个傻精灵耍了
Out-smurfed by a simpleton.
-她来啦  -蓝妹妹来啦
-She's coming. -Smurfette's coming.
-噢 不 被她看到了惊喜就毁了
-Oh, no! The surprise will be ruined.
蓝色警报 蓝色警报 重复一遍 这不是演习 蓝色警报
Code blue! Code blue! Repeat, this is not a drill. Code blue.
快还原啊 取掉胶水
Undo it, unglue it!
我们要把她引到别的地方去
We gotta get her out of here!
她来了 大家自然点
Here she is! Act natural!
嗨 伙计们
Hey, guys.
有没有人想在这特殊的日子里找点乐子吗
Anyone want to do anything fun on this special day?
嗨 靓靓
Hey, Vanity.
想不想坐在喷泉旁 欣赏自己的倒影呢
Want to sit by the fountain and look at your reflection?
我看自己都快看烦了 蓝妹妹
Kind of tired of looking at myself, Smurfette.
才怪呢
As if.
停下来 所有人现在全都停手
Nope, not building anything for anybody.
-你好 策划精灵  -你好
-Hey, Party Planner. - Hey.
-你好 公关精灵  -怎么了 亲爱的
-Hey, Social Smurf. - Yes, darling?
接下来有什么有趣的事情可以告诉我的吗
Anything fun coming up that I should know about?
没有 蓝精灵狂欢节之前没什么好期待的了
No, nothing till Smurf A palooza.
到时候可以好好疯玩一下 对吧 公关精灵
It's going to be wild, right, Social Smurf?
对啊 我已经把它放在蓝精灵网页上了
Yeah. I've got it all over the Smurf Web.
蓝蓝网上已经有101个赞了
It's got 101 likes on Smurf book.
到时候你会在宾客名单上哦
I will put you on the guest list.
所以 没人记得我的生日吗
So, no one remembered my birthday?
惊喜要被毁掉了啊
The surprise is gonna be ruined!
小声点 小声点
Hush up! Hush up!
你知道吗 蓝妹妹 有时候呢
You know, Smurfette, occasionally,
独处一下也是件不错的事情呢
it's good to have a little alone time.
-对的 去远足下什么的  -对啊
-Yeah, so take a hike. -Yeah,
我们这里很好 暂时不需要你
we don't need you here, we're good.
-再见了  -去吧
-Bye. -There you go.
再见
See you.
我们完全把她蒙在鼓里了 是不是啊 蓝笨笨
We fooled her pretty good, don't you think, Clumsy Smurf?
当然 她完全没发现这个惊喜派对
Yeah! She's got no idea about the surprise party!
伙计
Dude.
或许我根本就不属于这里
Maybe I really don't belong here.
* 祝你生日快乐 *
Happy birthday to you.
* 祝你生日快乐 亲爱的蓝蓝 *
Happy birthday dear Blue.
* 祝你生日快乐 *
Happy birthday to you.
好的 吹蜡烛吧 蓝蓝
Okay, blow out the candles, Blue.
真棒
Nice.
好的 我想所有人的情况我都考虑到了
Okay, I think I've got everyone's issues covered here.
这是一个有机的 无麸质 富含抗氧化剂的阿萨伊浆果蛋糕
This is an organic, gluten-free, antioxidant-rich acai berry cake
在本地制造 面包师傅十分温和
made locally by a cruelty-free
而且他发誓他根本就没见过花生
baker who swears he's never even seen a peanut.
大家都满意吗 没问题吧
Everybody good? Right?
-这些盘子都不含有多氯联苯吗  -哦不
-Are these plates PCB-free? -No.
-事实上 没问题的  -事实上 看这个 无多氯联 无双酚A
-Actually, we're good. -Actually, we're good. PCB and BPA-free.
爸爸 我们可以切蛋糕了吗
Daddy, can we cut the cake?
-可以  -好的 来切蛋糕吧
-Yeah. -All right, let's do that.
切吧
Cut it.
天啊 谁能想到当父母这么复杂啊
Boy, who thought parenting could be so complicated?
-好吃  -说认真的吗 你们两个
-Yummy. -Seriously, guys?
你们让带小孩看起来很轻松
You guys make it look easy.
没错 你们肯定是有个好榜样吧
Yeah, you must have had a great role model.
不 其实没有
No, not really.
-我老爸在我五岁的时候抛弃了我 所以...  -我迟到了吗
-My dad took off when I was five, so... -Am I late?
我错过了拆礼物环节吗
Did I miss all the presents?
嗨
Hey!
-维克多爷爷  -嗨
-Grandpa Vicster! - Hey!
生日快乐 蓝蓝
Happy birthday, Blue.
这才像个派对嘛 大家好啊
Now it's a party. Hello.
我是维克多 帕特里克的爸爸
I'm Victor, Patrick's dad.
你们一定都是他的朋友吧 他的朋友就是我的朋友
And you must all be his friends, which makes you my friends.
所以来吧
So let's go.
手都举起来 让我抱抱你们
Arms in the air, you're all getting hugs.
嗨 好吧
Hey, okay.
你刚才好像说你爸爸离开你了
I thought you said your father left you.
没错 这是我的继父
He did. This is my stepfather.
你会想让他离开的 等着吧
You'll want him to leave. Just wait.
你好 我的格蕾丝在哪里呢
Hello. Where's my Grace?
-嘿  -维克多
-Hey. -Victor.
最近怎么样
How are you?
你知道的 蓝蓝出生以后
You know, ever since Blue was born,
我就有点怀念那个挺着大肚子的你啊
I kind of miss you being as big as a house
抱起来更舒服呢
with more of you to hug.
好吧
Yep.
然后现在 最大的拥抱留到最后哦
And now, I've saved the biggest hug for last.
注意距离 求你了 有点底线啊
Boundaries, please. Boundaries.
咱给他们表演一个
Let's show them how it's done.
放开我
Unhand me.
我 一 点 都 不 喜 欢 这 样 啊
I don't like this at all.
谢谢你
Thank you.
道尔家男人们的拥抱 无与伦比啊
There's nothing like the embrace of two proud Doyle men.
我不姓道尔
I am not a Doyle man.
我的小帕蒂•道尔
Little Paddy Doyle.
-是温斯洛  -好吧 我妥协了 温斯洛
-Winslow. -Okay, compromise. Winslow.
温斯洛-道尔
Winslow-Doyle.
嘿 他是不是那个玉米热狗电视广告里面的家伙
Hey, isn't he the guy from the Corndog commercials on TV?
-嘿 没错  -好吧 被你们发现了
-Hey, you're right. -Well, you got me.
-玉米热狗之王  -不 不 不
-Korndog King. - No, no, no.
-等一下  -千万不要啊
-One moment. - Please not this.
现在 为了庆祝蓝蓝的生日
Now, in honour of Blue's birthday,
我要给大家每个人
I'm going to present each
一个免费玉米热狗
and every one of you with a free Korndog...
-谢谢你  -我请客
-Thank you. -...on the house.
秘制酱烧热狗
Teriaki dog.
这是给你的
That's for you.
这里面有花生吗
Do these have any peanuts?
我的玉米热狗里面从没放过花生
I would never put peanuts in a Korndog.
太好了
Great.
吃吧 大个子 可以吃
Go ahead, big guy, it's okay.
非常简单 想想看 我们用花生油把它炸的透透的
For the simple reason, you see, we deep-fry them in peanut oil.
花生油吗
Peanut oil?
-什么  -约翰尼 吐出来 马上吐出来
-What? -Johnny, spit it... Spit it out right away!
好的 我来打急救电话 别急
Okay, I got the phone, okay.
吐出来 约翰尼 马上吐出来 吐到妈妈手上来
Spit it out, Johnny! Spit it out right away! Into Mama's hands.
深呼吸 来一针肾上腺素
Deep breath for the EpiPen.
-会没事的  -这孩子的嘴唇是怎么了
-It's okay. -What's happening to that kid's lips?
-阿兹猫 把我的计划书拿过来  -爸爸
-Azrael, bring me my plan. - Father?
就在浴室里 看看在不在洗手盆旁边
It's in the bathroom. Check my side of the sink.
爸爸
Father?
该喂我们了
It's feeding time.
汉库斯晕乎乎
Hackus dizzy.
对的 我差点忘了
Yes, I almost forgot.
很显然 我还要养活你们俩个
Apparently, I have to keep you alive.
我希望你们懂得感恩
I hope you both appreciate
你们对于我来说是多么沉重的负担啊
what a tremendous burden this is upon me.
好吧 要有礼貌
All right, mind your manners.
非常感谢
Thank you.
如果你们是真的蓝精灵 我就可以从你们身上提取精华了
If you were real Smurfs, I'd be taking essence from you.
我没听见你说"谢谢"
I didn't hear a "Thank you."
勉强算是吧 来 快过来
Close enough. Come, come.
今晚突袭蓝精灵村之前我们还得再过一遍计划
We must review my plan before tonight's raid on Smurf Village.
这才不是我的手稿 我的计划书呢
This is not my writing parchment. Where is my plan?
"变成了电子版"
"Gone digital"?
我听不懂你说的啥意思
I don't understand what that means.
好吧 第一步 "制造淘气精灵" 没错
Yes, phase one, "Create Naughties." Yes.
完成 第二步在哪里
Check. Where is phase two?
啊 建造通往蓝精灵村的传送门
ah create portal to smurf village
这滑来滑去好像很爽啊
I am enamoured of that swiping motion.
对的 走开 走开 走开 走开
Yes, get away, get away, get away, get away.
第三步 划一划
Phase three... Swipe.
抓住我那没良心的女儿
I capture my ungrateful daughter
逼她告诉我
and force her to tell me the
蓝爸爸把她变蓝的神秘配方
secret formula that Papa used to turn her blue.
再划
Swipe.
把你们变蓝 再造上几百个你们这样的全都给变蓝
I turn you and hundreds other like you blue.
汉库斯变蓝啦
Hackus blue!
然后把你们放进一个可怕的机器里 吸出你们的精华
I place you into a terrifying machine and extract your essence.
-什么  -再然后
-What? -And then,
我就能统领全世界啦
the entire world shall bow before me!
吸精华的那个 会疼吗
Will that extracting thing hurt?
那可是极其折磨的... 不疼
It's excruciating...ly painless.
到时候你就知道了 好玩着呢 对我来说
You'll see, it'll be fun, for me.
好啦 反正咱还没到那一步
Anyway, we're getting ahead of ourselves.
回到第二步 我们千里迢迢
Back to phase two, the very
跑到这个一股臭奶酪味的城市来 就是为了它
reason we came to this cheese-infested metropolis.
大铁塔的尖
The great iron spire.
只有用这个办法
The only possible way
才能聚集足够的能量
to harness enough energy to create
建造一个通往蓝精灵村中心的传送门
a portal right into the heart of Smurf Village.
传送门发明 我的最爱
How I love portal creation.
动起来 快 到铁塔尖上去
Come, come, let us away! To the iron spire!
成功啦
It worked!
太好了 精华正好够用
Yes! Just enough essence!
创造历史的时刻来啦
And now I will go down in history!
没有什么能阻挡我啦
Nothing can stop me now!
我的格格蛋啊
My Gargaberries!
啊 不
Oh, no!
现在就来证明 我是个天才
Now I shall prove my genius!
转转头
Head spin!
看来我的精华还不够
It appears I lack sufficient
造出的传送门太小 人过不去啊
essence to create a human-size portal.
爸爸 我能钻过这个洞 让我去抓蓝妹妹吧
Father, I can fit through there. Let me get Smurfette.
让汉库斯去 汉库斯想去
Hackus go! Hackus go!
-嘿  -让汉库斯去
-Hey! -Hackus go!
都想去是吧 那就
Yes, yes. Well, let's see here.
-挑兵挑将...  -选我 选我
-Eeny, meeny, miny... -Pick me! Pick me!
打仗
Moron.
耶
Yes!
-嘿 汉库斯 我有话跟你说  -什么
-Hey, Hackus, listen to this. -What?
我赢了
I win.
这招漂亮 维可西
Nicely played, Vexy
好了 我警告你啊
Now, I must warn you.
你要去的地方恐怖至极
Your destination is a true horror.
那里空气中充满了让人窒息的和平与安静
A realm filled with the relentless crushing quiet of peace,
偶尔还有刺耳的欢快声音穿插在里面
punctuated by the wretched cacophony of joyousness.
-太可怕了  -简直就是噩梦
-It's horrible. -What a nightmare.
对 对啊 那里彻底毁掉了你姐姐
Yes, yes, it completely ruined your sister.
坏姑娘变好真是太丢人了
It's such a shame when a bad girl turns good.
说得好
So true.
但是她知道那个秘方
But she does know the secret formula,
去把蓝妹妹抓来
so go get Smurfette!
我真是想不通
I just don't get it.
他们明知道生日这一天对我来说有多不好过
They know how tough my birthday can be,
可他们就压根没记起来
and they didn't even remember.
也许爸爸错了
Maybe Papa was wrong.
也许我永远也没办法真正融入他们
Guess I'll never really be one of them.
-噢 不  -救命
-Oh, no! -Help.
求你了 别走
Please, wait.
我逃了出来
I escaped.
逃出来
Escaped?
从那个创造了我的坏巫师手里
From the evil wizard who made me.
你是说格格巫吗
Do you mean Gargamel?
格格巫是你爸爸吗
Is Gargamel your father?
是
Yes.
但是他...
But he's...
也就是说你跟我是一样的
That means you're just like me.
-抓到你啦  -你要干什么
-Gotcha! -What are you doing?
爸爸会很开心的
Father's going to be very happy.
蓝妹妹出事了
Smurfette's in trouble!
-不好啦  -噢 不
-Crikey! -Oh, no!
-快 蓝精灵们  -蓝妹妹
-Come on, Smurfs! -Smurfette!
不
No!
-哦 别想跑  -不
-Oh, no, you don't. -No!
-放手  -进去吧你
-Let go! -Now get in there!
哦 不
Oh, no!
-她被绑架了  -放开她
-She's being smurf-napped. -Unhand her!
再见了 蓝精灵们
So long, Smurfs.
-蓝妹妹  -蓝妹妹
-Smurfette! -Smurfette!
现在可怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
根据我的演绎法推断
My powers of deduction lead
这一定是格格巫干的好事
me to believe that this is the work of Gargamel.
啊 啊 啊 不
Oh, no, oh, no!
-成啦  -好漂亮的蓝色
-Yes! -Pretty blue.
格格巫
Gargamel.
蓝妹妹 欢迎回家
Smurfette. Welcome home.
你这是在浪费时间 格格巫
You're wasting your time, Gargamel.
爸爸他们会来救我的
Papa and the others are gonna come for me.
我可不觉得
I don't think so.
他们之前都去救笨笨了
They came for Clumsy.
是啊 但是你想想 笨笨是个货真价实的蓝精灵
Yes, but you see, Clumsy was a real Smurf.
你呢 却是我创造出来的
Whereas I was the one who created you.
还记得吧 啊 亲爱的
You do remember that, don't you, dear?
你不是我爸爸 放我回家
You're not my father. Just let me go home.
当然可以
Of course.
你想干什么都行
Anything you say,
但首先呢 我需要一个小小的
but first, I will need one itsy-bitsy,
微不足道毫不起眼的小东西
teeny-tiny little thing first.
-很小很小哦  -什么
-Teeny-tiny. -What?
就是蓝爸爸把你变成
Just the secret formula
一个真正蓝精灵的秘方
that Papa used to turn you into a real Smurf.
汉库斯要做蓝精灵 汉库斯变蓝
Hackus real Smurf. Hackus blue!
像你那样 金发妹
Like you, blondie.
这对咱俩都有好处 你说是吧 亲爱的
It would benefit us both, don't you see, my dear?
你给我配方 我把我的淘气精灵变蓝
You give me the formula, I turn my little Naughties blue.
-变蓝哟  -我取他们的精华
-Blue. -I use their essence
继续在这做我的魔术表演
to continue with my wonderful magic show here.
这样我就再也不用打扰你和蓝精灵村庄啦
That way I never have to bother you or Smurf Village again.
我不相信你 我什么都不会告诉你的
I don't trust you, and I'm not telling you anything.
是吗 看来需要好好劝劝你啊 哈
Well, perhaps you need a little persuasion, eh?
淘气精灵 上
Naughties, attack!
乐意效劳
With pleasure.
攻击
Attack!
-不不不 不是互相打  -打错人啦
-No, no, no, not each other. -Not me!
抓到你了...
I got you...
汉库斯
Hackus!
小猫 小猫 小猫
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
不是打猫 不是...
Not the cat, not the...
这些实验品真让人失望 失望透顶
Deeply, deeply disappointing experiments.
我们得去把蓝妹妹救出来
We've got to rescue Smurfette.
怎么把她带回来
What's our plan to bring Smurfette home?
好的 蓝精灵们 听好了
All right, Smurfs, listen up.
上次蓝月亮满月的时候
I saved enough grotto water
我留了足够的洞穴之水 就是为了以防万一
from the last blue moon for just such an occasion.
我用魔法把它们灌进了蓝精灵传输水晶里
I was able to smurf it into smurfportation crystals.
也就是说你不需要传送门了 爸爸你真聪明
So you don't need a portal. Very clever, Papa.
必了个须的
Smurf-xactly.
这些水晶能直接把我们传送到到温斯洛先生的蘑菇房里
These will take us directly to Master Winslow's mushroom.
对啊 帕特里克和格蕾丝上次
Yeah, Patrick and Grace helped
也帮我们通过了传送门
us last time we smurfed through the portal.
说的对 他们肯定知道怎么做
Precisely! They'll know what to do!
-我要去  -我报名
-Sign me up! -Sign me up.
-为您效劳 爸爸  -选我
-At your service, Papa. -Pick me!
-有人说过"面包师该去"吧  -我还是不去了
-Did someone say, "Baker should go"? -I would rather not.
我 我 选我 爸爸
Me, me, pick me, Papa!
别着急 蓝精灵们 我的水只够做九块水晶
Now, now, Smurfs. I only had water enough for nine crystals.
只够我和另外三个人的来回
That's me and three others round trip,
再加上蓝妹妹的回程
plus Smurfette on the way home.
那你也得先找到她 你又找不到
Assuming you can find her, which you won't.
你的态度太不像蓝精灵了 厌厌
That's not a very smurfy attitude, Grouchy.
其实对我来说 这已经算不错的了
Actually, for me, that was pretty good.
我需要勇气 智慧和力量
I'll need courage, intelligence and strength.
-勇勇  -好叻
-So Gutsy. -Aye.
-聪聪  -当然了
-Brainy. -Of course.
-健健  -你放心吧
-Hefty. -You got it.
-你们三个跟我走  -那个 我能...
-You'll smurf with me. -Yeah, can I...
怎么了 蓝郁郁
Yes, Passive-Aggressive Smurf?
我带上聪聪真是个好主意
I think Brainy is a really excellent choice.
祝你们好运啊
Good luck with that.
你看看他在干什么
You see what he does?
-那可不是在表扬我  -自己猜吧
-That's not a compliment. -Go figure.
-好了 健健 拿一颗  -我们行动吧
-Okay, Hefty, take one. -Let's do this.
-快去救她  -啊呀
-go get her, guys! -Oops!
笨笨
Clumsy.
谁想想办法啊
Somebody do something!
让开 我会蓝精灵抢救术
Stand back! I know the Smurflich manoeuver.
他看起来不妙啊
He doesn't look good.
哦 天 他变得更蓝了
Oh, dear, he's turning blue-er.
不好了
Not good.
谁去拿我的锤子来
Somebody get my hammer!
看你干的好事 笨笨
Nice going, Clumsy.
放着我来
I got it!
好呀
Cheerio!
本来应该是健健的
This was supposed to be Hefty!
对不起啊 爸爸
Sorry! My bad!
我一出门就容易浮肿的
I get so puffy when I travel.
拜
Bye.
呃 有时候 计划赶不上变化啊
Well, sometimes, you got to smurf with the changes.
一路顺风 爸爸
Travel safe, Papa.
就这样爸爸带着他的候补小队
And so Papa and his B team...
你不在的时候村子就交给我了
I'll be in charge while you're gone!
-就这样爸爸  -把蓝妹妹救回来
-And so Papa... -Go get Smurfette back!
-让我说完啊  -把她带回家
-Come on! -And bring her home!
他的喉咙通畅了 嘴唇也恢复了原样 太好了
I'm glad his throat opened up and his lips are back to normal.
我们真的很抱歉
Again, we're so sorry.
如果... 喂
If... Hello?
强尼又可以呼吸了
Johnny can breathe again, which
我也总算松了口气 因为他父母都是律师
makes two of us since both of his parents are lawyers.
呃 怪不得他们反应那么过激
Well, that's why they overreacted.
他们没有反应过激
They didn't overreact.
他快死了
He's dying.
我觉得你该戴上这个了
I think it's time for this.
别告诉我你把皇冠带来了吧 别给他戴皇冠
You didn't bring the crown. Don't put the crown on him.
别这样 你以前很喜欢这个皇冠的
Come on, you used to love this crown.
-我才没有呢  -真的 你特别喜欢
-No, I didn't. -Yes, you did.
-你走哪都戴着它  -我没有
-You wore it everywhere. -I did not.
从来没有 一次也没有
Never did. Never once.
这样做才对...看着
This is the way you do it... Look.
你看到外面在干嘛了吗
Do you see what is going on out there?
嗯 他们在增进感情呢
Yeah, they're bonding.
-严格来说 他们是在吐口水  -别这样嘛
-Technically, they're spitting. -Come on.
蓝蓝应该知道他的家人不止是你和我而已
Blue needs to know that family's not just you and me,
他跟爷爷一起玩玩多好的啊
and it's really good for him to play with his grandfather.
干的漂亮
Good job!
-嗯 就是 他可真是个好榜样  -别这样 帕特里克
-Oh, yeah. He's a terrific role model. -Come on, Patrick.
格蕾丝 他什么东西都能毁
Grace, he ruins everything.
到处走 到处毁 他就是这样的人
He shows up, and he ruins things. That's what he does.
就像他刚刚搬进我家的时候
Just like when he first moved into my house.
他把我的鹦鹉送走了
He sent my parrot away.
你有鹦鹉
Your parrot?
是我爸爸的鹦鹉
My father's parrot.
我爸爸离开的时候 他留下了宙斯 我好喜欢那只鸟
When my dad took off, he left Zeus, and I loved that bird.
那时候我还小 宙斯是我爸爸唯一留下的东西
I was a kid, and Zeus was the only part of my dad I had left.
这就对了
There you go.
什么东西
What?
保护蓝蓝 蓝蓝
Get Blue. Blue?
蓝蓝
Blue?
蓝蓝 维克多
Blue! Victor!
-呆着别动  -维克多 蓝蓝在你那吗
-Stay there. -Victor, do you have Blue?
维克多 我们打不开门啊
Victor! We can't get the door open!
维克多
Victor!
-维克多 开门啊  -维克多 我们打不开门啊
-Victor, open the door! -Victor, we can't open the door!
我看不见 我看不见
I can't see! I can't see!
我在一个黑漆漆的没有生命的星球上 闻起来一股玉米热狗味
I'm on a dark, lifeless planet that smells like corn dogs!
噢 我晕了
Oh, the smurfanity.
对不起 先生 你的脸挡着路了
Sorry, mister. Your face got in the way.
-那是笨笨吗 蓝精灵们来了  -笨笨
-Is that Clumsy? Smurfs? -Clumsy?
-救命啊  -小心啊厌厌
-Help! -Look out, Grouchy!
-笨笨 是你吗  -这边
-Clumsy, is that you? -This way!
-我瞎了  -不是 你困在玉米狗里了
-I'm blind! -No, you're in a corn dog.
我就知道没什么好结果
I knew it would end this way!
我在哪
Where am I?
这地方好奇怪 好吓人
This place is strange and terrifying
还很帅
and so handsome.
你好啊 帅哥
Hello, you.
-大家都没事吧  -有事
-Everyone ok? -No!
我们在黑暗中迷路了 周围还有一股玉米热狗味
We're lost in the dark, and it smells like corn dogs!
小心
Watch out!
温斯洛先生变老了啊
Master Winslow's gotten old.
-等等 等等  -蓝蓝
-Wait, wait, wait. -Blue?
住手 快住手 他们是朋友
Stop, stop, stop. They're friends.
-朋友  -对
-Friends? -Yeah.
他们这些蓝色小外星人 想要偷走我们的脸
They're little blue aliens trying to steal our faces.
不 不是的 他们是蓝精灵
No, no, they're called Smurfs.
他们是世界上最可爱的小东西
And they are the sweetest little things you ever did see.
我不是
Not me.
嗯 你不是 厌厌
No, not you, Grouchy.
蓝爸爸 笨笨
Papa, Clumsy.
-帕特里克  -温斯洛先生
-Patrick! -Master Winslow.
-嗨 格蕾丝  -蓝精灵 蓝精灵 蓝精灵
-Hi, Grace. -Smurf, Smurf, Smurf!
-那是蓝蓝吗  -他可真大呀
-Is that Blue? -He's huge.
哪个鹳如果被他骑着肯定要累死了
I wouldn't want to be the stork that brought that guy.
西方传说 小孩子都是由鹳鸟送到父母那里 蓝精灵也是被鹳鸟带去村庄
好吧 如果蓝蓝喜欢蓝精灵 那维克多也喜欢
Well, if Blue likes the Smurfs, then Vicster likes the Smurfs.
你们见到我一定很激动吧
What a thrill this must be for all of you.
谢绝照相 谢谢合作
No pictures, please.
这是靓靓
That's Vanity.
自恋狂
Narcissist.
你们来这儿干什么
What are you guys doing here?
蓝妹妹被抓走了
Smurfette's been taken.
-等下 啥  -抓走了 你说抓走了是什么意思
-Wait, what? -Taken? What do you mean "Taken"?
他被可怕的格格巫抓走了
Smurf napped by that ghastly Gargamel.
她自己在外面溜达 因为她觉得我们忘了她的生日
She was off alone because she thought we forgot her birthday.
这是一个误会
There was a misunderstanding.
不过如果我们找到格格巫 就能找到蓝妹妹了
But if we can find him, we'll find her.
呃 这个不难 他现在可是大明星
Well, that shouldn't be hard. He's a big star now.
-他人在巴黎  -我去找人来照顾小狗
-He's in Paris. -I'll call the dog sitter.
你去拿蓝蓝的护照
You get Blue's passport.
太好了 营救行动 我也去
Yes, a rescue mission. I'll come, too.
人多好办事
You need all the help you can get.
你等下 蓝蓝的护照
Wait a minute, Blue's passport?
巴黎不能这样说去就去吧
We can't just up and go to Paris.
至少不能所有人都去啊
At least, not all of us.
好吧 有一票反对 谁投赞成票
Okay, so that's one vote no. Who votes yes?
-我  -当然了
-Me. -Of course.
每次都是爸爸输
Daddy always loses.
听着 这可是我的蓝妹妹 我们必须去
Look, this is my Smurfette we're talking about. We have to go.
如果我们要出远门
If we're going to be travelling,
那就一定要按照蓝精灵的惯例来
let's make sure we do this properly.
啦啦啦啦啦啦 唱支快乐歌
La la la la la la sing a happy song
High Life by Nelly Furtado/Ace Primo
好了 我们到了 维克多 你能带着蓝蓝吗
Okay, here we are. Victor, can you get Blue?
-好的 大家都清楚计划了 对吧  -对
-All right. We're all clear on the plan, right? -Yeah.
我们去看格格巫的表演
We'll head over to Gargamel's show
-看看蓝妹妹在不在那  -对
-and see if Smurfette's there. -Yes.
然后我去格格巫的宾馆
And I'll go to Gargamel's hotel
想办法找到他住的房间
and see if I can find out what room he's in.
维克多 你和蓝蓝先去开房间住下
And, Victor, you and Blue can just check into the room here.
-呃 其实呢 我想着...  -不 没有"其实...我"不行
-Well, actually, I was thinking... -No. "Actually, I" Nothing.
你和蓝蓝 上楼去
You and Blue, upstairs.
说好了的 没得商量
That's the deal. End of story.
去歌剧院 有劳了
L'Opera House, s'il vous plait.
我说法语很性感 对不
My French is tres sexy, non?
对啊 也许可以给你戴上个贝雷帽
Oui, maybe I'll get you a beret.
我戴上贝雷帽 你可把持不住呢
You cannot handle me in a beret.
你这么觉得吗 我不能...
Is that what you think? I can't...
嘿 去开房吧你们
Hey! Get a shroom.
-祝你好运  -你也是
-Good luck. -You, too.
好
Okay.
把配方给他
Give him the formula.
你很想给他的
You want to give it to him.
给了他你就会很开心的
You'll feel better about yourself
别再摆出一副讨厌的小屁孩的样子了
if you stop being such anannoying little brat
还有把配方给他
and give him the formula.
啦啦啦 啦啦啦
lalala lalala
让她住嘴 真闹心啊
Make her stop. It burns.
汉库斯把知道的都告诉你
Hackus tell you everything I know.
汉库斯啥也不知道
Hackus doesn't know anything.
咋回事
What? What?
"缓冲" 啥意思...
"Buffering"? What the...
崇拜者们在等我了
My public awaits.
又得去应付那帮只会傻乐的弱智 让他们又震惊又迷惑
Once again I must go astound and confound the merry imbeciles.
你说我的精华用光了是什么意思
What do you mean, I'm out of essence?
我们还是可以表演的 放心吧
We can still do the show, all right.
因为现在我们需要的精华就在这个房间里了 对吧
Because we got all the essence we need right here now, don't we?
我只需要剪一点
I'm going to need a little snip.
哦 不
Oh, no!
只剪下耳朵旁边的一点点
Just going to take a little off around the ears.
好了
There.
等我的蓝爸爸来 他会要你好看的
When my Papa gets here, you're gonna be sorry.
你那位蓝爸爸不会来了 因为你的亲爸爸就在这儿
Your Papa is not coming because your real Papa is already here.
-对  -现在
-Yeah! -Now,
你要么做个乖孩子 老实把配方交给我
you can either be a good little girl and give me the formula,
要么你这悲惨的下半辈子就呆在这里
or you can spend the rest of your miserable little existence
给我的新超能力蓝精灵精华提取机做口粮吧
being harvested inside my new superpowered Smurfalator!
完全由你决定哦 真的
Your call entirely. Really.
都听你的
UP to you.
父亲 父亲大人
Father! Father!
太棒了
Yes!
做得好 小东西
Nice work, my dear.
至于你 想得美啊
And as for you, nice try.
好啦 阿兹猫
Yes, Azrael.
你可以按那蓝精灵精华提取机上的按钮
You can press the button on the Smurfalator.
快走快走
Come, come, come!
我们用这点头发榨出蓝精华
We'll brew this hair into Smurf essence!
蓝爸爸 快来救我啊
Papa, please hurry.
我好怕
I'm so scared.
可怜虫要哭了
Poor baby's gonna cry.
你好啊 小美女
Hello, pretty lady.
汉库斯也很漂亮哟
Hackus pretty, too.
-嗨  -你好
-Hi. -Hello.
我想问下
I was just wondering if you
你能不能帮帮忙告诉我...
could be so kind as to tell me what room...
格格巫先生住在哪个房间对吗
What room Monsieur Gargamel is in?
不行 这是酒店的规定
No. Hotel policy.
就停这边吧 谢谢
Just right over there. Thanks.
我们到了 大伙 巴黎歌剧院
Here we are, guys, the Paris Opera House.
-还不算太破嘛  -格格巫在这边还真混得不错啊
-Not too shabby. -Gargamel's really come up in the world.
希望蓝妹妹在这儿
I hope Smurfette's here.
我很爱高雅的音乐剧呢 真害羞哟
I do love a good musical. Guilty!
-他刚才说什么  -鬼知道啊
-What did he just say? -I have no idea.
有请伟大的巫师格格巫
Ladies and gentlemen, the Great Gargamel!
等等 等一下 给我停一下
Well, wait a minute, wait a minute.
我要的效果是神秘气息笼罩全场 这点烟雾糊弄谁呢
I asked for a shroud of mystery. This is a wisp!
阿拉卡扎气氛变
Alakazatmosphere!
我的天啊
Holy smurf!
这是怎么回事
Where did that come from?
他之前从没有过这么多的能量
He's never had this much power before.
我十分不满意
Well, I am outraged!
极其的不满意
Positively outraged.
不好意思 您是哪位
I'm sorry, who are you?
我是格格巫先生的经纪人 朵雷特女士
I am Monsieur Gargamel's manager, Madame Doolittle.
就这种窝棚你们也敢叫房间
What is this outhouse you call a room?
-您是说拿破仑套房吗  -拿破仑套房啊 对
-The Napoleon Suite? -Napoleon Suite? Yes.
但是女士 这是我们酒店最好的房间了
But, Madame, this is the finest room in all the hotel.
你是哪里不满意呢
What could possibly...
首先 亲爱的 这个楼层就不对
Well, for starters, darling, it's on the wrong floor.
没人愿意住在...
No one wants to be on the...
-五楼  -对 就是 这也太低了
-The fifth floor. -Yes. Yes, that's much too low.
哦 天啊
Oh, boy.
晚上好 晚上好
Good evening! Good evening!
好了大家 我们现在进去
Okay, guys, we're going in.
不不不
No,no,no.
先生你不可以进来
You may not be in here.
-你会说英语吗  -抱歉 不会
-Do you speak English? -No, I'm sorry.
太好了
Great.
蓝爸爸 这个人完全听不懂我在说什么
Okay, Papa, sneak out the back of my sweater
趁我俩聊天的时候 从我的毛衣后面滑出去
while I talk to this man who has no idea what I'm saying
找到他的化妆间
and go find that dressing room.
这真是个完美假期啊
This is a great vacation, guys.
我紧张得都快化掉了
I can feel the stress melting right off me.
-别叽歪了 厌厌  -是啊 我们能做到的
-Don't spiral, Grouchy. -Yeah. We got this.
-先生们 猫咪警报  -下来 快下来
-Gentlemen, we have a cat problem. -Get down, get down.
就这样 不 别害怕
There! No, no, don't be alarmed.
批评我的人都是这下场
This is how I treat all the critics.
快 从绳子爬上去
Hurry, up those ropes.
为了救个蓝妹妹值得吗
Is Smurfette really worth all this?
-我就随便一说  -我们走
-I'm just saying. -Let's go.
-没有许可 禁止入内  -什么 这也太过分了吧
-Not permis. Not permis. -What? This is outrageous.
你们的家人将会付出巨大的代价
Your families will all pay dearly.
最后 你们有些人会死
As a result, some of you may die.
-您好  -您好
-Bonjour! -Bonjour!
-你需要刷门卡  -嗯 谢谢 好啊
-You need your card. -Yes, thank you. It's good.
抱歉 您需要刷门卡
No, I'm sorry, you will need your key card.
当然啦 亲爱的 我的门卡啊
Yes, of course, darling, my key card!
天啊 我弄丢了
Oh, dear, I've left it.
啊哦 我之前在蒂凡尼吃了个早饭
Oui, I was having breakfast at Tiffany's.
奥黛丽•赫本的著名电影《蒂凡尼的早餐》
我还是回去拿吧
I'll just go back and get it.
员工换衣间
我爬绳子时 臀肌一定很好看
I bet my glutes look great climbing up this rope.
厌厌 看路
Grouchy, take a look.
我讨厌我的人生
I hate my life.
-笨笨  -快爬
-Clumsy! -Move it.
...打断了我的魔法 至少能逗我一笑
...Interrupt my sorcery, at least I should be amused.
现在 你们都会很发自内心的
Now, you will all kindly hail
为伟大且富有魔力的格格巫喝彩...
to the great and exceedingly powerful Gargamel...
你出来干什么 胆子大了啊
What are you doing out here? How dare you?
你闻到奇怪的味道了 那有什么奇怪的
You smell something suspicious? Well, of course you do!
别以为我不知道你平时都把鼻子放哪
I've seen where you put your nose.
快 滚出去
Now, get out of here.
嘿 爸爸
Hi, Daddy.
-蓝蓝  -嗯 嗯 听着
-Blue? -Yeah, yeah, yeah, just listen...
蓝蓝和我决定不能让你一个人单独行动
Blue and I decided we can't let you run solo on this.
我们要一起
We can do this together.
三位道尔家的男人
Three generations of proud
要自豪地并肩作战
Doyle men standing shoulder to shoulder.
即使我们身高什么的完全不同
Even though we're all different heights and whatnot.
我们不姓道尔
We are not Doyle men.
温斯洛-道尔
Winslow-hyphen-Doyle.
你就是不敢正视你的全名
You have a bee in your bonnet about the whole name thing.
你们在笑什么
Why do you chortle?
通常 在表演魔术的时候 猫不都是很大的吗
Usually, in magic, the cats are big, no?
就像老虎或者狮子那么大
Like tiger or like lions, you know?
安静点 混蛋 我会大发慈悲地满足你的
Silence, knave! And allow me to oblige you.
阿拉卡扎猫猫变
Alakazanimal!
尽量别让自己闻着太香
Try not to smell delicious!
目前看来 这是我这辈子最糟糕的旅行
So far, this is the worst trip of my life!
我总共就旅行过两次
And I've only taken two!
-快看 格格巫的化妆间在那  -眼神不错 靓靓
-Look! There's Gargamel's dressing room. -Good eye, Vanity.
拜托 居然在门上贴了个五角星
Please! He's got a star on his door.
我们走
Let's go.
回去记得提醒我也在我的蘑菇门上贴个五角星
Remind me to put a star on my mushroom when we get home.
-如果我们想要变成蓝色的话...  -蓝色
-If we ever want to be blue... -Blue.
...必须得想个办法让她松口
...we've got to come up with some way to get her talking.
-是啊  -想到什么了吗
-Yeah. -Got any ideas?
我知道了 跟她说"求你了"
I got it! Say "Please."
算了吧 我忘了你是 你
Never mind. I forgot you were you.
-听好我的计划  -好的
-All right, here's my plan. -Okay.
我们想办法把她变成跟我们一样 变得淘气
We trick her into acting like us, being naughty.
淘气 淘气
Naughty, naughty!
我们利用她的善良来对付她
We use all her goodness against her.
一旦我们成功了 她就会觉得和我们是一家人了
Once that happens, she'll feel like she's part of our family!
一家人 我喜欢家人
Family! I like family!
我喜欢这计划
I love this plan!
-噢 不  -家庭破碎了
-Oh, no! -Broken family!
-抓住她  -抓住她 抓住蓝妹妹
-Get her! -Catch her! Catch Smurfette!
再见了 捣蛋鬼们
See you later, Smurfigators!
爸爸会杀了我们的 快追
Father's gonna kill us! Go faster!
-再会了 丑八怪  -抓住她
-Au revoir, trolls! -Get her!
-有人吗  -蓝妹妹
-Hello? -Smurfette?
-你在哪啊  -问个小问题
-Where are you? -Quick question.
既然我们能爬这么高 为什么不去用门把手
How is it we can't reach a doorknob, but we can get up here?
不 笨笨 不要啊
No, Clumsy, don't! No, no!
你刚刚被空气打败了
You just lost a fight to an empty room.
怎么都没人上来陪猫咪玩
Nobody wants to come up here
你们那些刚才吵吵嚷嚷强烈要求要更大猫咪的人呢
and play with the larger kitty that they so annoyingly asked for!
你得走了 快点
You have to go! Now!
-好的 只要找到蓝妹妹我们就走  -是的
-Yeah, soon as we get the Smurfette. -Yeah!
-就算它把你吃掉了 你也会被它咳出来的  -嘿
-He coughs up everything he eats. -You!
变戏法的 给我把蓝妹妹交出来
Magic man, hand over the Smurfette.
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say?
没听到吗
You heard me.
给我把蓝妹妹交出来 快点
Give me the Smurfette! Now!
你怎么敢 阿拉卡...
How dare you? Alaka...
-闪开鸭  -鸭鸭变
-Duck! -...duck!
鸭鸭变
Duck?
这咋...回事啊
That was...up.
不
No!
是你
You.
我的个祖师爷啊 我认得你
By great Merlin's beard, I remember you!
我们又见面了 哈
We meet again, eh?
爸爸飞起来了 爸爸飞起来了
Daddy's flying! Daddy's flying!
好了 好了 好了 看来我们终于找到了一位志愿者
Well, well, well, it appears we have a volunteer after all!
巡游的差不多了 嘴张开 阿兹猫
Enough fooling around, yes? Open wide, Azrael.
放他下来 格格蠢货
Put him down, Gargafella!
放开我儿子
Leave my son alone!
我来给你上一课吧 别招惹我们道尔鸭
I'll teach you to mess with us Doyle ducks!
又是你
You again!
你干什么 放我下来
What are you doing? Put me down!
快走 蓝蓝
Come on, Blue.
放我下来 我马上就要搞定他了 就差一点点
Put me down! I could have taken him! I had him!
恐怕今天的演出就到这里了
I'm afraid that's all the show we have time for.
再见
Good bye.
赶紧的 都出去吧 快滚吧
Go on, get out, get out, get out.
这是蓝妹妹的头发 她来过这里
Smurfette's hair. She's been here.
快看 我找到了什么
Look! I found something.
一副完美的肖像画
A portrait of perfection.
想象一下 如果你在帮忙的话看起来就更帅了
Imagine how good you'd look if you were actually helping.
长的帅又不是我的错 谁让大家都爱美呢
Don't hate the player, hate the game.
-蓝妹妹  -蓝妹妹
-Smurfette? -Smurfette?
嘿 这是咖啡吗
Hey, is that coffee?
有谁想要来一别咖啡哦
Anyone else want a cup 0' joe?
嘿 那是啥
Hey, what's that?
这是面镜子 你这个乡巴佬
It's a mirror, you barbarian.
别臭美了 靓靓 快推
Snap out of it, Vanity, and push!
坏脾气优先 帅脸蛋接后
Rage before beauty.
不知道这是什么 但是让人毛骨悚然的
Whatever this is, it's making my butt scrunch.
有点吓人 我是说...
That's a little scary. I mean...
格格巫
Gargamel!
笨笨 你想害我们被抓吗
Clumsy! Are you trying to get us smurfed?
这大概是什么魔法窗口
It's some sort of magic window.
也许它会告诉我们蓝妹妹在哪呢
Maybe it'll show us where Smurfette is.
淘气精灵
Naughties?
-是格格巫  -快 拿着走
-Gargamel! -Quickly, pick it up.
快 这边 这边
Quickly, to me, to me!
蓝妹妹 有人吗
Smurfette? Hello?
跑哪去了 在吗
Where did you go? Hello?
-快点 孩子们  -他过来了 快点
-Move, Smurfs. -Here he comes. Hurry.
-快啊 快啊  -你们跑哪去了 还在吗
-Let's go! Let's go! -Where are you? Are you here?
-孩子们 蓝妹妹  -往后 往后
-Children? Smurfette? -Back up, back up.
关门 快关门
Close the door! Close the door!
你们的爸爸回来了哦
Your papa is back.
她的爸爸
Her papa?
如果这是个玩笑 我告诉你我可一点都不喜欢
If this is a joke, I assure you I don't find it funny.
-有人吗  -拿住了
-Hello? -Hold it!
-你们在下面吗 你们这些小混蛋  -站稳了
-Are you down there, you little delinquents? -Keep still.
他们肯定是逃回酒店去了
They must have retreated back to the hotel.
我们肯定没多少时间了
Of course we're running out of time.
如果帕特里克在这里 那蓝爸爸一定也在附近
If that Patrick person is here, then Papa cannot be far behind.
快点 回酒店去 我们一定要在蓝爸爸之前赶到
Quickly, to the hotel! We must get to her before he does.
我的脸啊 我的脸啊
My face! My face!
-怎么了  -简直帅呆了
-What? -It's gorgeous.
我们摔下来了 这次居然不是我的错
We fell, and it wasn't even my fault!
有人吗 有人吗
Anyone? Anyone?
我的老天啊
Oh, my Smurf.
我又开始发抖了
I'm scrunching again.
爸爸 这些东西和蓝妹妹有什么关系
Papa, what does this have to do with Smurfette?
恐怕 这一切都是针对她的
Everything, I'm afraid.
他为什么要造这么恐怖的机器
Why would he build such a hideous device?
那是个超大的蓝精灵精华提取机吗
Is that a giant Smurfalator?
是用来提取我们的精华的
To extract our essence.
这些容器又是用来做什么的
What are all those containers for?
九十九个用来囚禁蓝精灵的瓶子
Ninety-nine bottles of Smurf on the wall.
那么如果蓝妹妹把配方给了他...
So if Smurfette gives him the formula...
他就可以把淘气精灵
He can turn as many Naughties
变成蓝精灵 他想要多少有多少
into Smurfs as his greedy heart desires.
伙计们
Guys?
蓝精灵末日
total smurf a geddon
哦 天哪
Oh, dear.
扶我一下 拜托
Need a catch, please.
这地方真需要加强回收啊
This place really needs to recycle.
快动脑子 蓝妹妹 快想想 哦 不
Think, Smurfette, think. Oh, no!
-蓝妹妹哪去了 哪去了  -她在那
-Where's Smurfette? Where's Smurfette? -There she is!
她跑得真快 我喜欢这个游戏
She's fast! I love this game!
慢着 就让她跑她的 她也没地方可去
Wait! Let's let her run for a bit. She's got nowhere to go.
-这太有利于我的计划了  -好的 好的
-This is perfect for my plan! -Yeah, yeah.
你生的什么气 被变成鸭子的是我
What are you so cross about? I'm the duck!
你总是半路杀出来 把一切都搞得乱七八糟
You always barge in and ruin everything!
你就是个扫把星
You're like a walking disaster!
嘿 看着我的眼睛认真的说一遍
Hey, look me in the eyes and say that.
-我做不到  -这就对了 因为你说的不对
-I can't. -That's right, because it's not true.
不 是因为你的眼睛长在了脑袋的两边
No, I can't because your eyes are on the sides of your head!
所以我更能看出你对我一点也不尊重
All the better for me to see your disrespect!
-你们看什么看  -快走吧
-What are you looking at? -Hurry up.
这都是全球变暖造成的 赶紧买辆普锐斯吧
It's global warming. Buy a Prius.
普锐斯 丰田汽车公司的一款混合动力车
好的 我甩掉他们了吗
Okay. Did I lose them?
乖狗狗
Good dog.
哦 不... 抱歉 不好意思
No, no... Sorry. Excuse me.
好的 我能行的
Okay, I got this.
爸爸 你在哪啊
Papa, where are you?
从下水道离开格格巫的老窝
Why am I not surprised the way out of
真是一点也不奇怪
Gargamel's lair is through a sewer?
-温斯洛先生  -蓝爸爸
-Master Winslow. -Papa!
-帕特里斯 快看  -怎么了
-Patrick, look. -What happened?
格格巫正在酝酿一件非常非常糟糕的计划
Gargamel is hatching a terrible, terrible plan.
这鸭子是怎么回事
What's with the duck?
那是维克多 格格巫把他变成鸭子了
That's Victor. Gargamel turned him into a duck.
-现在格格巫已经知道我们来了  -我只是想帮忙而已
-Now Gargamel knows we're onto him. -I was only trying to help!
维克多 你看着真纠结
Victor, you look fowl.
foul纠结 和fowl家禽 读音相同
我这么说了 我就这么说了
Yes, I did. Yes, I did.
大家集中精神 我们得快点找到蓝妹妹
Focus, everyone. We've got to find Smurfette quickly.
-她在那里 终于找到了  -去追她吗
-There she is! Got her! -Chase over?
嘿 汉库斯 看到那个糖果店了吗
Hey, Hackus. See that candy store?
-糖果 有糖果耶  -我有主意了
-Candy? Candy! -I've got an idea.
去闯祸吧
Go get yourself in trouble.
去捣乱吧 剩下的我来搞定
Be naughty! I'll take care of the rest.
我喜欢闯祸 捣乱 捣乱 爱捣乱
I love to make trouble! Naughty, naughty, naughty!
嘿 金发妹 你要去哪啊
Hey, blondie. Where you going?
离我远点
Leave me alone.
像你所谓的爸爸那样吗
You mean like your so-called Papa has?
他才没有
No, he hasn't!
他会来找我的
He will come for me.
他不会来的 因为他知道你已经回到真正属于你的地方了
He won't, because he knows you're where you really belong.
我没有绑架你 蓝妹妹
I didn't kidnap you, Smurfette.
我把你带回家了
I brought you home.
Tutti Fritti by Buckwheat Zydeco
我要大闹一场
I'm gonna make big trouble.
美味的糖果
Yummy candy!
麻烦来啦
Here comes trouble!
你好呀
Hello!
我的天呐 他会被杀死的 我们得去帮帮他
Oh, my gosh! He's gonna be killed! We have to help!
我还以为你是个好人
I thought you were supposed to be good.
但是...
But...
救命啊
Help!
哦 天啊
Oh, smurf.
好吧 快走
Okay, come on!
哦 不 我现在真摊上麻烦了
Oh, no. I'm really in trouble now.
-维可西  -哦不 汉库斯
-Vexy! -Oh, no! Hackus!
救命啊
Help!
救救汉库斯
Help Hackus.
蓝妹妹 我们该怎么办啊
Smurfette, what are we gonna do?
维可西 把我弹上去 快来 跳
Vexy, give me a lift! Come on, jump!
-正中靶心  -我的老天
-Bull's-eye! -Holy smurf!
-好身手 蓝妹妹  -搅拌那个去吧 糖果人
-Good one, Smurfette! -Blend that, candy man!
快来 汉库斯
Come on, Hackus!
维可西 我们走
Vexy, let's go!
抓稳了
Hold on!
小心啊
Look out!
干得好啊 偷了一辆推车
Nice move, stealing a cart.
我不是故意要偷的啊
I didn't exactly steal it.
-对不起  -但这不是你的推车啊 不是吗
-Sorry! -Well, it's not yours, is it?
捣乱 捣乱 捣乱
Naughty, naughty, naughty.
看到没 你简直和我们一模一样
See? You're just like us.
我要怎么样才能让蓝妹妹
How am I going to get Smurfette to
把配方告诉我呢 阿兹猫
give me that formula, Azrael?
这件事简直让我想...
This whole thing just makes me want to...
哭吗 才不是 我想把她放到马桶里冲掉
Cry? No. Flush her down the toilet bowl.
肯定有什么办法的
There must be something we can do.
我知道你那点小小的脑子
I know you only have a tiny
跟豌豆差不多大 但是快想想
little pea-sized brain in there, but think!
今天是她生日吗 真的吗 关我屁事
Is it her birthday? Really? Who cares?
送个礼物吗 送个蛋糕吗
A present? A cake?
对她好一点吗
Be nice to her?
给点甜头 拍拍马屁让她的铁石心肠软下来 对吗
Bribery and flattery to soften her stony little heart, eh?
听起来真不是我的作风 但是有可能会成功啊
That's counterintuitive, but that just might work.
我简直太英明神武了
I'm so glad I thought of this!
让我想想...
Let's see...
好了好了
All right, all right.
我该送她什么礼物呢
What kind of gift should I get her?
-猫咪 猫咪 猫咪  -嘿 满嘴鱼腥味的家伙
-Kitty, kitty, kitty! -Hey, fish breath!
别闹 阿兹猫 我在想要送什么礼物
Not now, Azrael, I'm trying to think of
显得又真诚又体贴
a genuine and heartfelt gift
来蒙蔽蓝妹妹呢
that I can deceive that Smurfette with!
我说了别闹
I said not now!
别闹 别闹 别闹 别闹
Not now! Not now! Not now!
你自己走回去吧
You are walking home.
臭猫
Cats.
快一点 再快一点
Faster! Faster!
劳驾 对不起
Excuse us! Sorry!
要怎么把这玩意儿停下来啊
How are we gonna stop this thing?
我觉得应该不难
I don't think that's gonna be a problem!
安全着陆
And she sticks the landing!
-美味的布丁  -汉库斯 这是泥巴
-Yummy pudding! -Hackus, it's mud.
美味的泥巴
Yummy mud!
放马过来啊 臭猫
Take your best shot, cat!
小心
Watch out!
太棒了
Yes!
-干得漂亮 我们走  -干得漂亮 我们走
-Nice shot! Let's go! -Nice shot! Let's go!
-快走  -再不走就迟了 汉库斯
-Come on! -Move it or lose it, Hackus!
哦不 生气的猫咪 生气的猫咪 快跑
Oh, no! Angry kitty! Angry kitty! Run!
好的美女们 展示下你们的肚子
Okay, ladies, act pregnant.
-这边 伙计们  -快点
-This way, guys! -Faster!
-现在该要飞了  -快点
-It's time to get your wings! -Faster!
快点 到鹳鸟身上去
Quick, get on the storks!
我们走
Let's go!
等下 汉库斯在哪里
Wait, where's Hackus?
快飞啊 大鹳鸟 快飞
Fly, big stork, fly!
猫咪来啦 小心啊
Here comes kitty! Look out!
来吧 汉库斯 我们走
Come on, Hackus! Let's go!
耶
Yeah!
嘿快看 落水猫
Hey, look, it's a catfish!
再见咯 猫咪
Bye, kitty!
简直太棒了
This is amazing!
鹳鸟在向后飞 鹳鸟在向后飞
Stork going backwards! Stork going backwards!
真是太美啦
This is so beautiful!
我掉下去了 我掉下去了
I'm falling! I'm falling!
蓝妹妹是我的英雄
Smurfette's my hero!
-事情怎么样了  -实在是太棒了
-How did it go? -Couldn't have gone better.
只不过所有事情都是大灾难而已
Except that everything was a complete smurftastrophe.
这就是蓝精灵定律
It's Smurfy's Law.
我倒是有个好消息
Well, I have some good news.
我给你搞了一套服务员的衣服
I borrowed a waiter's outfit for you,
包括一张坐电梯用的门卡
complete with a security card for the elevator.
你是怎么做到的
How did you manage that?
这么说吧 国际服装检查员
Let's just say that the Plaza Athenee
朵雷特小姐小小地拜访了一下
laundry room was paid a little visit
雅特尼大酒店的洗衣房
by international apparel inspector Mademoiselle Doolittle.
我简直就像梅丽尔•蓝精灵•斯特里普
I was like Meryl smurf in' Streep.
梅丽尔•斯特里普 著名好莱坞女明星
干得漂亮 格蕾丝
Good job, Grace!
是每个人都有新衣服 还是只有帕特里克有呢
Does everyone get a new outfit, or just Patrick?
-该死的窗户  -那是什么
-Bloody window. -What was that?
是维克多
That's Victor.
保安不让他从大厅里进来 所以他飞上来了
They wouldn't let him through the lobby, so he flew up.
眼睛撞瞎了
No depth perception.
维多多爷爷是一只鸭子
Grandpa Vicster is a duck!
格格巫对他施了咒语
Gargamel zapped him.
你能把他变回来的对吧
You can change him back, right?
不能 不过这是个变形咒语
No, but it's a transformation spell.
过一段时间就会消失的
It'll wear off eventually.
大家放轻松啦 这根本不是问题
Everybody relax. It's not a problem.
但是如果谁看到我下了个蛋 那就别到处宣扬了
But if you see me lay an egg, it's just between us.
你好像并不难过啊
You don't seem too upset about this.
鸭子天生不会难过
It's not in a duck's nature to get upset.
我们喜欢把事情抛在脑后
We like to let things roll off our backs.
真的吗 你是认真说的吗
Seriously? You seriously just said that?
-我喜欢 你很像蓝精灵  -非常像
-I like that. That's very smurfy of you. -Very smurfy.
是吗 谢谢你 看见没
Why, thank you. See?
这个圣诞老人蓝精灵欣赏我
The little Santa Claus Smurf appreciates me.
或许有一天 帕特里克
Maybe someday, Patrick,
你也能学会欣赏我身上的蓝精灵特质
you'll learn to appreciate my smurfy qualities, too!
好吧 我... 这实在... 算了吧...
Okay. I've... There's... You know...
我才不要和一只鸭子讨论这个
I'm not having this conversation with a duck.
现在我又感冒了
Now I'm catching a cold.
我还希望我感冒了呢
I wish I had a cold.
健健的水晶滑进了我的喉咙
I've had Hefty's crystal shoved down my throat,
我被一只玉米热狗袭击 还掉进了下水道
got attacked as a corn dog, fell down a sewer,
这还不算最臭的
and if that wasn't smelly enough,
我还被夹在腋窝里走来走去
had to travel by armpit
最后发现我们要灭绝了
just to find out we're all gonna be extinct!
-我的老天爷啊 我是个消极者  -相当正确
-Holy smurf, I'm a downer. -You most certainly are.
厌厌 只有蓝妹妹把秘方交给了格格巫
Grouchy, the only way we'll be extinct is if Smurfette
我们才会通通灭绝
gives Gargamel the secret formula.
-但是蓝妹妹一定不会说的  -当然不会
-But Smurfette would never tell. -Of course not.
-不可能的  -绝对不会
-Never. -Absolutely not.
蓝妹妹不可能被骗 成为他们的一员的
Smurfette could never be tricked into being one of them.
嘿 蓝妹妹
Hey, Smurfette.
在蓝精灵村 你会和你的姐妹一起这样玩吗
Did you do this with your sisters back in Smurf Village?
我经常飞 但是我没有姐妹
Lots of flying, but I never had a sister.
好吧 你现在有姐妹了啊
Well, you do now.
This Is What Rock N Roll Looks Like by Porcelain Black
-想要比赛吗  -你想和我比赛啊
-Want to race? -You want to race me?
那你可小心了
You're in trouble now!
-我要甩掉你了 蓝妹妹  -想都别想
-I'm gonna lose you, Smurfette. -Not a chance.
看好啦
Watch out!
抓紧了 汉库斯
Hold on tight, Hackus.
-别抓这么紧啊  -对不起
-Not that tight, Hackus. -Sorry.
长空击鹳
Stork fight!
我们来了
Coming through!
这太疯狂了
This is insane!
蓝精灵飞啊飞
Smurf, smurf, and away.
乘鹳之王 汉库斯
Hackus, king of world!
你开始耍阴招了啊
You're playing dirty now!
这才是刚开始呢
I'm just getting started.
冲啊冲
GO, go!
好一个薄煎饼蓝妹妹啊
I call that a Crepe Smurfette.
外带一份蜗牛吗
Snails to go?
-连续开火  -来啊
-Batter up! -Come on!
好好瞄准了再打啊
Hit me with your best shot.
搞定她了
Snailed her!
-你可真会捣蛋啊 蓝妹妹  -那当然
-You are naughty, Smurfette. -Yeah.
嘿 我在哪儿见过这个女人
Hey! I've seen that lady before.
她长的真漂亮
She's beautiful.
好像哪儿都有她
They've got one of these everywhere.
我要掐死那个该死的鸭子
I'm gonna strangle that duck.
维克多就像衰神附体一样到处跟着我
Vic's like a black cloud that follows me around.
好吧 听着 我知道你想说什么
Okay, look, I get it.
但是你得这样想 他来了不是吗
But you know what, he's here, isn't he?
他最终还是来了
He shows up.
是啊 不管你到底想不想要他来 他都会来
Yeah, whether you want him to or not.
好吧 但是人们常说一位父亲只要能陪着孩子就不错了
Okay, I always heard that showing up was 90% of the job.
有很多父亲甚至都做不到这一点
A lot of fathers don't even do that.
可他不是我的父亲
He's not my father.
那太可惜了
Well, that's too bad.
这样的话你就一个父亲也没有了
'Cause that pretty much leaves you without one.
-帕特里克  -好了 伙计们
-Patrick. -All right, guys.
-开始行动了  -开始吧
-Game on. -Let's do this!
-我在这陪着蓝蓝  -也看着点维克多
-I'm gonna stay with Blue. -And Vic.
好了 孩子们 准备向格格巫的酒店出发
Okay, Smurfs, off to Gargamel's hotel.
帕特里克 事实上有些事情...
Patrick, there's actually something I'd like to...
没什么"事实上"
No "Actuallys."
你就待着这
You're staying here.
这根本不是我想...
That's not what I was even going...
维克多 别逼我揍你
Victor, don't make me pluck you.
-我们走吧  -行动吧
-Let's go. -Let's do it.
我们这次肯定能把蓝妹妹救出来
We're gonna get Smurfette this time, 100% guaranteed.
你刚才说了什么 厌厌
What did you just say, Grouchy?
你听到我说什么了 我开始有点讨厌做厌厌了
You heard it. I'm tired of being Grouchy.
我要转变风格做个积极向上的精灵了
I am changing my tune to a happy one.
我宣布 从现在起 我就是...
From now on, lam...
准备好了没 蓝喜喜
Ready? Positive Smurf.
我笑的时候好像伤到脸了
I sprained my face.
你会慢慢习惯的 我们出发了 孩子们
You'll get used to it. Let's go, Smurfs.
-来吧 来吧  -一个纸袋子 这待遇真"不错"啊
-Come on. Come on. -A paper bag. First-class.
-快一点  -笨笨
-Hurry... -Clumsy!
祝你好运 爸爸
Good luck, Daddy!
尊敬的阿兹猫
Le chat VIP.
请让我带你去你的房间
Please, I will take you to your room.
-你好 这里是前台  -给我听好了 你这呆子
-Front desk. -Listen well, you slack-jawed knave.
格格巫先生
Monsieur Gargamel.
我要你们准备好麦芽酒 凝乳还有
I want ale, curds and
熟肉 在10分钟之内送到我的房间
blistered meats sent into my room in 10 minutes,
不然我就把你变成一只没腿的树懒
or I will turn you into a legless tree sloth.
学的像吧  蓝精灵们
How was that, Smurfs?
哥们 这一点都不好笑
That's not funny, man.
鸭子 鸭子 还是鸭子
Duck, duck, duck.
啊 一只鹅
Goose!
酒店电梯的门卡 看来帕特里克需要我的帮助
The security card for the elevator. Patrick needs my help.
哈哈  当我带着这个出现在他面前的时候
When I show up with this,
他会发现这所谓的衰神有时候还是能...
he'll see this black cloud has got a silver...
还是能给他带来好运的
A silver lining!
哦 我的...
Oh, my...
温斯洛先生 请你别分心好吗
Mr.Winslow, please.
-你根本不可能...   -集中注意力
-You can't get a reservation... -Focus.
这东西闻起来太香了
That smells delish!
找到你了
Le bingo.
好了 伙计们 听着 等你们进入房间之后
Okay, guys, listen, when you get to the room,
如果遇到了什么问题...
if there's any problems...
-贝壳上沾点鼻涕 还美味呢  -对不起 鱼先生
-Snot on a half shell. Delicacy. -Sorry, Mr Fish!
你看起来好熟啊
You look fried.
听我说 如果你们碰到了什么问题的话...
Like I said, if there are any problems...
在我的字典里根本就没有问题这个词
My friend, there are no such thing as problems.
只要抓住机会 什么事情都能解决
Only smurfitunities.
-你别吓我 厌厌  -说了是喜喜
-You're freaking me out, Grouchy. -Positive!
当然...
Of...
好了 伙计们 我们进电梯了
Okay, guys, we're in.
帕特里克•温斯洛-道尔
Patrick Winslow-Doyle.
帕特里克
Patrick.
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我来帮你来了 快过来
Saving your tail feather. Now come here.
我给你带来了你现在最需要的东西
I've got something you need for your mission.
快点过来啊 没时间再和你废话了
Hurry up. There's no time to argue.
-到底是什么  -这是电梯的门卡
-What? -It's the security card for the elevator.
我带着门卡啊
I have the security card.
这是什么 这是我们房间的房卡
What is this? This is our room key.
呃 这样啊 那好吧 这样等会你回去的时候就用得上了
Well, now when you come back, you'll be able to get in.
-没关系的  -我没法...
-No problem. -I can't...
哦 不 不 不要
No,no,no,no,no.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
晚点再谢我也成
You can thank me later.
你是怎么逃出来的啊
How did you get out?
听着 你现在就把我放下
Now, you just put me back down.
帕特里克 帮帮我
Patrick, help!
-我等会要用你炖汤的  -你要把我宰了吗
-We need you for our duck a I'orange. -You want a piece of me?
哦 不 不 不 我不是那个意思
No, no, no, no! That's not what I meant.
没错 这一切都因为鸭子 不过马上 马上灾难就要降临了
Yeah, it starts with the ducks, and soon, no one's safe!
-简直难以置信  -帕特里克
-Unbelievable. -Patrick!
温斯洛先生
Master Winslow?
-帕特里克  -他去哪儿了
-Patrick! -Where'd he go?
-他不见了  -现在我们只能靠自己了
-He disappeared. -Now we're on our own.
-好吧...  -快藏起来
-Well... -Hide!
格格巫先生
Monsieur Gargamel.
这下我们完了 有谁准备了第二套行动计划
We're smurfed. Plan B, anybody?
别问我 我还在纠结现在怎么变得积极一点呢
I'm struggling to remain positive here.
格格巫先生
Monsieur Gargamel?
客房服务
Room service.
哦 您好啊 小猫猫
Hello, kitty.
这是您叫的客房服务
Here is your room service.
-我们现在该怎么办  -打他个措手不及
-What do we do? -Smurf him with the element of surprise.
哦 笨笨
Oh, Clumsy!
-哦 上帝啊  -现在我们怎么办
-Oh, dear. -Now what do we do?
我们得吓一吓他
Just act scary.
你说什么
What?
你好啊 我是个鬼啊
I'm a scary ghost!
干得漂亮
Nice.
这么多倒霉的事 怎么能发生在可爱的蓝精灵身上呢
Why do so many bad things happen to little blue people?
积极一点 积极一点
Positive, positive.
窗户 前面有窗户
Window! Window! Window!
哦 不是吧
Oh, no!
你开玩笑吧 你差一点就杀...
Are you smurfing kidding me? You nearly killed...
不过 你看看这风景
I mean, look at this view.
它看上去像只鸭子 叫起来像只鸭子
If it looks like a duck, quacks like a duck,
而且闻上去像个玉米热狗
and smells like a corn dog...
好了 哪一只是你 维克多
All right, which one of you is Vic?
什么 你连你自己爸爸都认不出了吗
What, you don't recognise your own father?
-我们走吧  -那我这些兄弟们呢
-Let's go. -What about my brothers?
我们不能把他们留在这里 等着被吃吧
We can't just leave them here to be eaten.
你们认识才多久啊
You just met them.
他们都是我的同伴 我不能丢下他们不管
This is my flock. I can't just leave them behind.
来了 如果你是个好人 那么我也是
Come on, if you're game, so am I.
我全身上下都是脏的
I am covered in filth.
瞧我这幅邋遢的样子
I look like something the cat dragged in!
此处原文cat双关
哦 不是吧 没这么难看吧
Come on, it's not that bad.
尽管 我不是... 阿兹猫
Although, if I don't... The cat!
-别打脸 别打脸  -快点把盖子盖上
-Not the face. Not the face! -Close the lid!
-这太棒了  -谢谢
-That was awesome! -Thank you!
汉库斯万岁
Hackus lives!
维可西 来帮我把门关上
Vexy, come and help me close the door.
-谢谢你了 大鸟  -再见
-Thank you, bird. -Bye.
这太刺激了
That was crazy.
再见了 鸟儿们 我玩的很愉快
Bye-bye, birds. I had fun.
太棒了
Yeah.
-蓝精灵击掌  -蓝精灵击掌
-High fours! -High fours!
汉库斯 汉库斯 汉库斯
Hackus, Hackus, Hackus.
身边有个女孩真不错
It's so nice having another girl around.
你干嘛呢你
What are you doing?
我只不过是抱抱你
I'm just hugging you.
你就没有被抱过吗
Haven't you ever been hugged?
维可西...
Vexy...
-汉库斯抱抱 汉库斯抱抱  -汉库斯
-Hackus hug. Hackus hug. -Hackus.
汉库斯抱紧紧
Hackus squeeze!
汉库斯
Hackus.
乐观的来讲 我们就该把他留这里头
I'm positive we should just leave him in here.
谢谢
Thanks.
赶快 他们十有八九
Hurry. They're probably doing
在对她做着什么惨无人道的卑鄙事情
something mean and horrible to her right now.
对啊 蓝妹妹需要我们 她也许正害怕又...
Yeah, Smurfette needs us. She's probably scared and...
-一家人最棒啦  -什么...
-I love family! -What...
她在做什么
What is she doing?
我猜他们在抱抱吧
I think they're hugging.
爸爸
Papa?
汉库斯爱抱抱
Hackus love to hug.
汉库斯
Hackus.
蓝妹妹 过来 给你看样好东西
Smurfette, come on, I got to show you something.
看看咱俩 来看 咱俩长的就像一家人
Look at us. Come on, tell me we're not family.
蓝妹妹
Smurfette!
看这边
Over here!
蓝妹妹
Smurfette!
很抱歉蓝爸爸没来找你
I'm sorry Papa Smurf didn't come for you.
不过也许你本来就属于这里 跟我们在一起
But maybe your place is here with us.
对啊
Yeah.
也许是呢
Maybe it is.
她怎么跟那些家伙那么亲
Why is she being nice to them?
她只是在与绑架者产生共鸣
She's just identifying with her captors.
典型的斯德哥尔摩综合症
It's classic Smurf-holm syndrome.
被害者对于犯罪者产生情感 甚至反过来帮助犯罪者的一种情结
不 她觉得我们不再关心她了 而那几个家伙在乎她
No, she thinks we don't care anymore, and they do.
她糊涂了
She's confused.
笨笨 厌厌 上去帮我把门打开
Clumsy, Grouchy, get up there, and help me get this door open.
-我闺女在里面呢  -好的 爸爸
-That's my daughter in there! -Okay, Papa.
-我去上面  -好的 厌厌你来跳 我来拉
-I'll get on top. -Okay, Grouchy, you jump, I'll pull.
-加油 没问题的  -孩子们
-Come on, we can do this. -Children.
-格格巫  -笨笨 别松手
-Gargamel! -Clumsy, don't let go...
爸爸回来啦
Daddy's home.
他心地特别善良 还给你带礼物了哦
And consistent with his kind nature, he brought you a present.
厌厌快下来 他会看见你的
Grouchy, get down. He'll see you.
-现在我们怎么救她  -嘘
-How are we gonna rescue her now? -Quiet.
我想我们之前有点误会
I do believe we got off on the wrong foot earlier.
咋回事
What's happening?
可不可以允许我祝我的小心肝生日快乐啊
Would you allow me to wish you a very, very happy birthday?
我还记得当年你只是
It seems like only yesterday
一团小粘土和一些烂材料的样子
you were just my little
这一切好像昨天的事儿一样啊
glob of clay and other putrid ingredients.
你记得我的生日吗
You remembered my birthday?
当然了 我们是一家人嘛
Of course I did. We're family.
-什么  -但我们才是她的家人
-What? -But we're her family.
她觉得我们不要她了吗
Does she think we abandoned her?
说到这 你那蓝乎乎的小个子
Speaking of which, your little
继父一直都没到 他现在来了吗
blue step-papa never did arrive, now did he?
继父
Step-Papa?
怎么搞的 我真为你很难过 亲爱的 你一定很痛心吧
Why, I am truly sorry, my dear. That must really sting.
我还记得我爸爸
I remember when my father
第一次把我扔到井里的时候
threw me down the well for the first time.
当我终于想尽了办法爬出来
The disappointed look on his
他那脸上失望的表情啊
face when I finally managed to claw my way out.
不提这些了 生日快乐 亲爱的
Anyway, happy birthday, my dear.
-生日快乐 蓝妹妹  -生日快乐 蓝妹妹
-Happy birthday, Smurfette! -Happy birthday, Smurfette!
-我要拆  -让我来拆  -不 不不
-I want to open! Let me open! -No, no, no.
丑死了
Ugly.
"鞠躬 给我跪下 崇拜我吧"
"Bow. Kneel. Worship me."
没错 学的不错 真不错
Yes, delightful rendition, really.
接着学 影帝 看我不把你搞的不省灵事
Keep it up, no-neck, I'll turn you into a cross-eyed newt.
没错 亲爱的
Yes, yes, my dear.
来啊 拿着它
Go ahead, take it.
属于你的神奇小小魔杖哦
It's a tiny little magical wand of your very own.
快 这是你的生日礼物呢
Go ahead. It's your birthday present.
不
No.
别拿啊
Don't do it.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
哎呀我太笨了 我忘记把它打开了
Silly me. I've forgotten to turn it on.
在这儿呢
Here we are.
对 这就对了
Yes, there we go.
好了 来 试一试 别害怕
Yes, go ahead, try it out. Don't be afraid.
-龙之魔杖  -哦 天呐
-A Dragon Wand. -Oh, dear.
毕竟 这就是你生来的使命
After all, it is your birthright.
你怎么知道我不会用它来对付你
How do you know I won't use it on you?
这个嘛...
Well...
因为 蓝妹妹 我是你爸爸啊
Because, Smurfette, I am your father.
仔细感觉一下 你知道的
Search your feelings. You know it to be true.
-她会打他的  -放倒他 蓝妹妹
-She's gonna zap him. -Get him, Smurfette.
蓝妹妹...
Smurfette...
唱啦啦歌
Sing The La La Song.
快唱
Sing it!
这是好事儿 是不 爸爸
This is good, right, Papa?
不 她要变成他们一伙的了
No! She's becoming one of them!
我一直想这么干来着
I have always wanted to do this!
我们要失去她了
We're losing her.
-好样的 蓝妹妹  -你的第一次欺负猫啊
-Yes! Good one, Smurfette. -Your first cat zap.
看看你哦 看看你
Look at you. Look at you.
你真是爸爸的好女儿
You truly are daddy's little girl.
-蓝妹妹  -不要 爸爸 厌厌 抓住他
-Smurfette! -No, Papa! Grouchy, grab him!
-不 爸爸 他会看见你的  -把他拽下来
-No, Papa, he's gonna see you! -Get him down!
-笨笨 帮我 帮我把他拉下来  -爸爸 不要啊
-Clumsy, help, help me get him down! -Papa,no!
好耶
Yeah!
不
No!
飞上天啦 终于自由啦 终于自由啦
Take to the skies, lads. Free at last! Free at last!
-你以为你是谁 马丁•路德•雯吗  -没错
-What are you, Martin Luther Wing? -That's it.
改自Martin Luther King "Wing"有翅膀之意
尽情的拿我开涮吧 搞笑君
Joke it up, funny boy, but I
但我很自豪自己是自由斗士
am proud as a peacock to be a freedom flighter.
哦 不
Oh, no.
那它嘎的是什么
What the...is that?
撑住 蓝精灵 维克多来啦
Hang on, Smurfs! Victor's on the way!
蓝精灵降落伞启用
Pop your smurf-chutes.
双翼飞翔式
The flying V!
接到啦
Gotcha.
哦哦 别慌张
Okay, don't panic.
好大一坨大白肉
That is a lot of white meat.
现在该慌了
Now panic!
好讨厌的感觉啊
Me no likey!
太精彩了
That was brilliant.
-他裸着呢 对吧  -大家都还好吗
-He's naked, right? -Everyone okay?
救命 有人吗 有人在吗 放我出去
Help me, somebody. Somebody please, let me out!
别问我在那下面看见了什么
I have seen unspeakable things down there.
小小的内心留下了不可磨灭的伤痕
I have been scarred for life.
蓝妹妹呢
Where's Smurfette?
-她...  -蓝妹妹呢
-She's. .. -Where's Smurfette?
我们去的 太晚了
We were too late.
你干的好事
Nice going.
好好玩啊 孩子们 记住 和平相处哦
Have fun, children. Just remember, be kind to each other.
你能不能离我远点 你个呜呜叫的蠢货
Will you get away from me, you bumbling moron?
-他们哪去了  -啥
-Where are they? -What?
蓝精灵来过吗 来这个屋子吗 你怎么不早说
Smurfs were here? In this room? Why didn't you say so?
我有机会说吗
Right now!
不能让她知道
She must not learn of this.
我们要把她骗走 现在就拿到配方
We must spirit her away from here and get that formula now.
蓝妹妹 亲爱的 你准备好去庆祝了吗
Smurfette, my dear, are you ready to go celebrate?
-好啊  -来吧来吧 一定很好玩
-Yeah! -Come on, come on. This'll be fun.
我们差一点点就能把蓝妹妹救回来了
We were this close to getting Smurfette back.
我知道
I know.
他就在这个节骨眼儿上给我找事儿 格蕾丝
He distracted me at the worst possible moment, Grace.
要不是他 我应该在电梯里面的
I would have been in the elevator if it wasn't for him.
好好 小声点
Okay, okay, use your indoor voice,
好了 帕特里克 深呼吸
and please, Patrick, just breathe.
我想让他走
I want him gone.
-他是你爸爸  -不 他根本不是
-He's your dad. -No, that's one thing he is not.
他说的对 格蕾丝 我不是他爸爸
He's right, Grace. I'm not his father.
他的亲生爸爸抛弃了他 组建了新的家庭
His real father left and started a new family.
他一直都过不去这个坎儿
He's been chewed up about it ever since.
-抱歉你说啥  -我是很抱歉
-Excuse me? -As well you might.
但是我没法再承受你的这种压力了
But I can't take the brunt of it anymore.
嘿 我从来没求着你闯进我的生活 好吗
Hey, I never asked for you to come barging into my life, okay?
我也没让你娶我妈妈 没让你把宙斯送走
I didn't ask you to marry my mother or take away Zeus.
宙斯 那只鸽子吗
Zeus? The pigeon?
是鹦鹉
The parrot.
我的鹦鹉
My parrot.
它被带走了 就因为你过敏
Taken away because you were allergic.
不是我对那只鸟过敏 帕特里克
I was not allergic to that bird, Patrick.
是 就是你
Yes, you were.
过敏的不是我
No, I wasn't.
是你
You were.
什么
What?
你当时症状很严重 每天都气喘 咳嗽
It got so bad, every day, you were wheezing, coughing.
你妈妈和我都知道 如果告诉你
Your mother and I both knew that it would break your heart
是因为你鹦鹉才被送走 你会很伤心
to think the bird had to go away because of you.
你已经为你爸爸的事而自责了
You already blamed yourself for your dad.
所以才说是因为我
So I took the heat.
不可能 你说什...我才不对鸟类过敏
That's a lie. What are you... I'm not allergic to birds.
好吧 试试
Okay, tell you what.
闻闻这羽毛
Sniff my feathers.
-我才不闻呢  -快点 闻闻
-I'm not going to... -Come on, sniff them.
事实如此 很痒 是吧
Truth itches, doesn't it?
听着 帕特里克
Listen to me, Patrick.
我真心实意爱你妈妈
I loved your mother with all my heart.
我尽心照顾珍妮特 努力让她开心
I took care of Jeannette, and I made her happy.
我也曾像爱亲生儿子一样爱你
I also chose to love you as my own.
其实我大可不必那么做
Now, I didn't have to do that.
可是你还那么小 没有父亲
But you were this little kid, no father,
眼里充满绝望 内心空虚无助
no hope in his eyes, a big hole in his heart,
所以我给了你我能付出的全部
so I gave you everything I could.
可是我不会再那么做了
But I'm done, you know?
你不接受我的爱 可以
You don't want it, that's fine.
我给你的最后忠告就是
My last word of advice to you is this...
能成熟点吗
Will you grow up?
不要再把自己的痛苦归罪于他人
Stop blaming everyone else for your pain.
无论你做什么
And whatever you do,
不要让你可爱的儿子觉得
don't teach that beautiful son of
爱是有条件的 因为爱是无条件的
yours that love is conditional, because it is not.
再见 格蕾丝
Good bye, Grace.
再见 蓝蓝
Bye-bye, Blue.
维克多爷爷
Grandpa Vicster.
再见
Bye.
再见 帕特里克•温斯洛
Goodbye, Patrick Winslow.
看那大轮子
Look at that big wheel.
来 跟我来 亲爱的
Come. Come along, my dear.
这就是为什么巴黎被称为光明之城
So this is why they call it the City of Light.
好多人啊
There's a lot of people.
是啊 不过
Yes, well...
我更喜欢叫他们"崇拜者"
I prefer to call them "Worshippers."
"崇拜者"
"Worshippers."
阿拉卡跪下
Alakakneel!
弯腰 跪下
Bow. Kneel.
汉库斯
Hackus.
-走吧  -我们走
-Shall we? -Let's go.
别担心 大家都喜欢这样 他是大明星 来吧
Don't worry. Everyone likes it. He's a celebrity. Come on.
好吧
Okay.
好哇 是我
Yes, hello. It's me.
-这些是我的孩子们  -嗨
-These are my children. -Hi.
-那是谁  -是我哥哥
-Who's that? -That's my brother.
嗨 我是汉库斯
Hi. I'm Hackus.
快看啊 多神奇的生物
Look at that. It's a magical creature.
嗨
Hi.
今天是我生日哦
It's my birthday.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我有免票特权  -对 免票特权
-I have a FASTPASS. -Yeah, FASTPASS.
格格巫先生
Monsieur Gargamel!
谢谢你们帮我们预热座位 再见啦
Thank you for keeping our seats warm. Goodbye.
再见
Bye-bye!
跟上 孩子们 这边来
Come along, children. Right this way.
格格巫先生 格格巫先生
Monsieur Gargamel! Monsieur Gargamel!
我们走
Let's go!
-爸爸  -等会
-Father. -Not now.
快到吃饭时间了
It's feeding time soon.
-不是现在  -可是
-Not now! -But
我们到了
Here we are.
-好戏才刚刚开始  -耶
-Our fun is just beginning, eh? -Yeah.
阿拉卡快动
Alakazelevate!
很漂亮 不是吗 亲爱的
But isn't this lovely, my dear?
想想看
And just think,
你的配方加上我强大的魔法
with your secret formula and my incredible magic,
天底下就没有我们做不到的事
there's absolutely nothing that we cannot do.
是啊
Yeah.
想象一下我们在一起有多欢乐吧 蓝妹妹
Think of all the fun we could have, Smurfette.
好吧
Okay.
那我们为什么还转得这么慢呢
Then why are we going so slow?
Vacation by G.R.L
-当心  -耶
-Look out! -Yeah!
多好玩啊
Isn't this fun?
一点也不好玩
Decidedly not!
真棒啊 蓝妹妹的开心游 哈
Best ride ever! Smurfette's fun, huh?
来啦
Incoming!
小心 过来啦
Look out! Coming through!
不好意思啦
Sorry!
我一定让她失望了
I must have failed her.
对不起 我只是想找个地方静一静
Sorry. I was looking for a place to think.
不 不 没关系
No, no, no, no. It's okay.
我也正在反思我自己
I was doing a little thinking myself.
温斯洛先生 这不容易开口
Master Winslow, it's hard for me,
不过 你能给我一些建议吗
but, well, can I ask you some advice?
作为一个父亲的建议
I mean, papa to Papa
是关于蓝妹妹的
It's about Smurfette.
我不知道该怎么办了
I don't know what to do.
我把她变蓝
I turned her blue.
教她爱与友善
I taught her love and kindness.
但事实上 是格格巫制造了她
But the truth is, Gargamel made her.
只要她愿意 她就是个蓝精灵
She's only a Smurf as long as she chooses to be.
可如果她不愿意呢
But what if she doesn't?
如果她选择了格格巫呢
What if she chooses him?
我们会失去她
We could lose her.
我们可能已经失去她了
We may have already.
是我做得不够好
I haven't done enough.
你开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
格格巫只是制造了她 可是你
Gargamel just made her, but you,
你成就了她
you made her what she is.
你无条件付出 视她如己出
You stepped in and loved her as your very own.
没有人要求 可你还是那样做了
No one asked you to, you just did.
因为你知道她需要那一切
Because you knew she needed that.
那是...
And that's a...
那是一种非常特殊的爱
That's a pretty special kind of love.
她那么聪明 不可能感觉不到的
She's way too smart not to see that.
你说得对
You're right.
我们并不是因为她变蓝了才信任她
We didn't believe in her because she changed.
她是因为我们的信任才变蓝的
She changed because we believed in her.
谢谢你 温斯洛先生
Thank you, Master Winslow.
这些正是我需要的
That was exactly what I needed to hear.
也是我需要的
Me, too.
再来点泡泡
Just a few more bubbles.
这样如何
How's that?
我的个天啊 你吃了什么啊
Sweet Smurf in Heaven, what have you eaten?
没关系 每次蓝精灵排放尾气 都有人如释重负
It's okay. Every time a Smurf toots, someone smiles.
-我们走 蓝精灵们  -去哪
-Let's go, Smurfs. -Where?
去救蓝妹妹
We're getting Smurfette.
可是你也看到她了 爸爸
But you saw her, Papa.
她现在是格格巫的人了
She's one of them now.
-是马语者了  -不是
-A horse whisperer? -No!
-是社会党了  -不是
-A French Socialist? -No!
是空中飞人了
A Flying Wallenda!
不 是格格巫的人了 拜托跟上思路
No, she's with Gargamel. Keep up.
我不管我们看见什么
I don't care what we saw.
我们永不放弃家人
You never give up on family.
对 爸爸说得对
Yeah, Papa's right.
你是谁 你把厌厌怎么了
Who are you, and what have you done with Grouchy?
嘿 我是喜喜 忘了吗
Hey, I'm Positive, remember?
好啦 孩子们 咱们出发吧
All right, Smurfs. Let's get smurfing.
温斯洛先生 和我们一起去吗
Master Winslow, you coming with us?
蓝精灵的屁股是蓝色的吗
Is a Smurf's butt blue?
你自己看
You tell me.
厌厌
Grouchy.
-快提上裤子  -谁还想看
-Put it away. -Anybody else?
好啦 出来吧
Okay, then. Out of the tub with you.
-我们还有正事要做呢  -嘿
-We've got work to do. -Hey.
打起精神 出发吧
Let's smurf this mushroom stand. Let's roll.
好的 兄弟们 加油
Yeah, guys, let's do this.
维克多 嘿
Victor? Hey.
Remember The Name by Fort Minor
好的 温斯洛先生 我们分头行动
Okay, Master Winslow, we'll split up here.
好的 我去找电控室把电源切断
All right. I'll find the electrical room and cut the power.
我们会找到蓝妹妹的
And we'll find Smurfette.
而且我们干活时都帅极了
And we'll all look fabulous doing it.
噢 行了吧
Oh, come on.
团队建设 好吗
Team building. Hello!
好啦 我们里面见 祝你好运
All right, see you inside. Good luck.
-来吧 伙伴们  -钻入野兽腹中
-Come on, guys. -lnto the belly of the beast.
为什么我们要下到这里呢 父亲
Why are we coming down here, Father?
这个嘛 我们要为你失散已久的姐姐庆祝生日
Well, we are celebrating your long-lost sister's birthday.
真的吗
Really?
如果没有蛋糕的话
Can't very well end the festivities
这个庆祝不能完美收官
without a cake.
我做了你最喜欢的 亲爱的 蓝丝绒
I made you your favourite, my dear. Blue velvet.
蛋糕啊
Cake.
来吧 许个愿 亲爱的
Go ahead. Go ahead. Make a wish, my dear.
你小小心中能梦想到的一切 都是你的
Anything your tiny little heart can dream of, and it is yours.
任何事吗
Anything?
当然
But of course.
嗯 好吧 合理范围内
Yes, well, within reason.
我担心我们这儿
I'm afraid we're on a bit
精华不太够
of an essence budget around here lately.
所以我们需要那个配方 你明白了吧
That's why we need the formula, you see.
她在那
There she is.
那是个生日蛋糕吗
Is that a birthday cake?
我们也为她准备了生日蛋糕
We had a birthday cake for her, too.
她只是没看到
She just never saw it.
他们看起来真像幸福的一家
They look like a happy family.
她不会把配方给他的 是吗 爸爸
She's not going to give him the formula, is she, Papa?
如果她给了 那就意味着我们整个蓝精灵种族的灭亡
If she does, it would mean the end of all Smurf kind.
等下 连帅哥也是吗
Wait. Even the handsome ones?
-是的  -靓靓 你跟我来
-Yeah. -Vanity, you come with me.
笨笨和厌厌 去跟温斯洛先生汇合
Clumsy and Grouchy, go meet Master Winslow.
维克多 你来这干嘛
Victor, what are you doing here?
格蕾丝给我打电话
Grace called me.
她说你可能需要帮忙
She said you might need a hand.
不 维克多 等下
No, no. Victor, wait.
跟平常一样 格蕾丝是对的
As usual, Grace is right.
我可能需要帮助
I could use some help.
好的 首先 你最好试试去撬下水道盖子
Well, for starters, you might try lifting the sewer cover.
除非你是准备修电话线
Unless you're planning on fixing the phone lines?
蓝妹妹 配方呢
Smurfette, the formula?
给你时间考虑 亲爱的
Take all the time you need, my dear.
只是不要让我等太久
As long as it's very, very soon.
然后我们就都可以变成蓝色了 一起
Then we can all be blue. Together.
汉库斯蓝色的 汉库斯蓝色的
Hackus blue. Hackus blue.
你看到了 他们想变成蓝色的
You see? They want to be blue,
就像他们的姐姐一样
just like their big sister.
然后我们就是真正的一家人了
Then we could be a real family.
这很重要
This is something.
是一个托付给我的神圣礼物
A sacred gift entrusted to me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是 我...
I just, I...
我不能
I can't.
你是什么意思 你不能
What do you mean, you can't?
我什么都给你了
I've given you everything.
善心 礼物
Kindness, presents,
没毒的蛋糕 这真可怕
a cake with no poison. It's been horrible!
现在 我已经受够了 小姐
Now, I have had just about enough of this, young lady.
你必须给我我想要的 现在
You are going to give me what I want right now!
-配方  -不
-The formula! -No!
必须
Yes!
-父亲  -干什么
-Father? -What, what, what?
汉库斯头晕
Hackus dizzy.
他们怎么了
What's happening to them?
好晕啊
So dizzy.
别跟我说你真在乎这些可怜的生物
Don't tell me you actually care for these pathetic creatures.
你真可悲
How sad for you.
不过这刚好对我有利
And how absolutely perfect for me.
电线好像是通往这边
It looks like the power lines run this way.
走 快走 我们要把她救出来
Let's go! Let's go! We got to get her out of there!
好的 行动吧
All right, let's do this!
走这边 靓靓 穿过这个管道
This way, Vanity. Through this pipe.
我们必须救她出来 这可是我大显身手的时候
We have to save her! This could be my moment!
抱歉 亲爱的 我以为你知道
I'm so sorry, my dear. I thought you knew.
没有精华 他们活不下去
Without essence, they cannot live.
-父亲  -不
-Father. -No.
求你了
Please.
不 维可西
No. Vexy.
好晕啊
So dizzy.
-汉库斯  -蓝妹妹
-Hackus. -Smurfette.
把你有的给他们 从我身上再拿点
Give them what you have! Take some from me.
拿走
Take some!
拜托了
Please!
这有什么用 你又不给我配方
What's the point? You won't give me the formula,
所以 好吧 我可能就管不了他们了
so, well, I might as well just let them go.
维可西
Vexy
你的意思是你会让他们死
You mean you'd let them die?
我总能再做些其他的
I can always make others.
而且 我不是那个让他们死的人
Besides, I am not the one letting them die.
你才是
You are.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
我会把它给你 只要你喂他们
I'll give it to you. Just feed them.
先给配方
The formula first.
快喂他们
Feed them. Feed them!
快点 我们必须进去这里
Quickly. We have to get in there.
死路 这里上锁了
Dead end! It's locked!
配方 啦啦啦啦啦啦
The formu-la-la-la-la-la-la.
一个充满希望的想法
One hopeful thought.
少许蜂王浆
A dab of royal jelly.
含羞草花粉
Mimosa pollen.
蓝妹妹
Smurfette.
-蓝妹妹  -真棒 好姑娘
-Smurfette! -Yes, good girl.
我能听到他们 但是看不到
I can hear them, but I can't see them.
等下 我知道了
Wait! I know.
爸爸 看
Papa, look.
-还有一滴貂油  -我知道这个
-And a drop of mink oil. -I knew it.
她在给他配方吗
Is she giving him the formula?
-噢 不  -蓝妹妹
-Oh, no. -Smurfette.
帮我把这个打开
Help me get this open.
然后你必须说一个爱的真理
And you must say one loving truth.
-当然  -好了
-Of course. -There.
这就是爸爸用过的魔咒
That's the formula Papa used.
现在 喂他们 求你了
Now, feed them! Please!
首先 我们得看看这个管用不 不是吗
First, we'll see if this works, huh?
快点
Hurry!
-过来  -我们到了
-Come on. -Here we are.
我们走
Let's go! Let's go!
拉 帕特里克 使点劲
Pull, Patrick. Put your back into it.
-快点  -嗨 这里下面有个开口
-Come on! -Hey, there's an opening down here.
-快来 喜喜  -我们来打败他们
-Come on, Positive. -Yeah, let's shut 'em down.
一个爱的真理
One loving truth.
希望这个管用
I hope this works.
汉库斯
Hackus.
-蓝妹妹 谢谢你  -维可西
-Smurfette. Thank you. -Vexy!
噢 我的天 起作用了
Oh, my Smurf, it worked.
-汉库斯  -汉库斯变蓝了
-Hackus! -Hackus blue!
汉库斯
Hackus.
汉库斯变蓝了
Hackus is blue!
我们变蓝了 我们变成蓝精灵了
We're blue! We're Smurfs!
成功了 这个世界是我的了
It worked. All the world is mine!
-我可以做自己的蓝精灵了  -不
-I can make my own Smurfs! -No!
她背叛了我们
We've been betrayed.
终于啊 终于啊
Finally, finally.
你成了真正的男孩
You're a real boy.
我变蓝了
I'm blue.
现在你们都给我进机器里去
Now into the machine with all of you.
父亲 不
Father, no.
-汉库斯不要笼子 汉库斯不要笼子  -行了 行了
-No cage for Hackus. No cage for Hackus. -All right, all right.
-进去吧  -汉库斯不要笼子
-In you go. -No cage for Hackus!
-每个人都有自己的房间  -求你了
-Everybody gets their own room. -Please!
-我让她失望了 靓靓  -爸爸 等下
-I failed her, Vanity. -Papa, wait.
我好像能够到那个插销
I think I can reach that pin.
好主意 靓靓
Good idea, Vanity.
加油 快点
Come on, come on.
父亲 求你了
Father, please.
现在 哪也不准去
Now, don't go anywhere.
你的脸哭哭
You face leaking.
汉库斯哭哭
Hackus leaking.
你牺牲了一切只为救我们
You sacrificed everything just to save us.
我必须这样做
I had to.
我在乎你们
I care about you.
我们是一家人
We're family.
不喜欢哭哭
No like leaking.
汉库斯喜欢蓝色
Hackus like blue.
多么令人作呕的一幕啊
What a sickening scene.
我可能早就狂吐不止了
I'd be completely nauseated if this weren't
可惜现在是我一生中最快乐的时刻
the happiest moment of my life!
-试试那个控制杆 大的那个  -到我肩上来
-Try the lever, the big one. -Get on my shoulders.
快点 小伙伴
Hurry, lads.
往哪边扳
Which way do I go?
试试负极 或许能关掉机器
Try negative. That might shut it off.
负极 呐 我现在只想要积极
Negative? Nah. I'm all about positive.
positive 可指积极自信也可指正极
好了
There.
巫师一小步
One small step for a wizard,
一大步... 怎么了
one giant leap for... What?
积极万岁
Positive!
蓝精灵莓子馅饼太多了
Too much smurf berry cobbler.
厌厌
Grouchy!
对了 我说了让你来按下按钮 是吧
Yes, I said you could press the button, didn't I?
厌厌
Grouchy!
我撒谎了 我的一大步
I lied. One giant leap for me!
被炸熟了
Just got fried.
想要对此积极起来有点难啊
Hard to put a positive spin on that.
狗精灵养的
Son of a Smurf!
快点 靓靓
Hurry, Vanity.
自恋就是为了今日的救赎
Narcissism is about to save the day.
-搞定了  -太棒了 开工
-Got it! -Smurftastic: work.
-我就知道  -快走
-I knew it. -Now go.
-什么  -快走
-What? -Go!
快点 阿兹猫
Come, Azrael!
显然 我们得最后再
Apparently, we must harness
整治一下天空的能量
the power of the skies one final time.
为什么这事儿弄得这么悲惨世界状
Why does this have to be so Les Miserables?
-咱们走  -瞧瞧我 会使劲会摔跤
-Let's go. -Look at me, all rough-and-tumble.
我是个突击蓝精灵
I'm like Commando Smurf.
呼哈
Hooah!
你说的对 突击队员都静悄悄鬼鬼祟祟的
You are right. Commandos are quiet and stealthy.
呼哈
Hooah!
-她在那儿  -蓝妹妹
-There she is! -Smurfette.
圣诞老人
Santa!
爸爸 你... 你来救我了
Papa? You... You came for me.
我们当然会来救你 你是我的女儿
Well, of course we came for you. You're my daughter.
难道有任何疑问吗
Was there ever a question?
-不 这个锁上了  -快过去
-No, it's locked. -Go on through.
-我们会找到别的路  -好
-We'll find another way. -Okay.
咱们在里面碰面 温斯洛先生 快走
We'll see you in there, Master Winslow. Hurry!
给
Here.
拿着
Hold this!
爸爸
Papa.
哦 我的宝贝
Oh, my dear.
爸爸 我给了格格巫那个配方
Papa, I gave Gargamel the formula.
但她救了我们的命
But she saved our lives.
汉库斯活着 汉库斯活着
Hackus live! Hackus live!
爸爸 我让你失望了
Papa, I let you down.
我背叛了蓝精灵
I betrayed the Smurfs.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
蓝妹妹 生命是最珍贵最值得保护的东西
Smurfette, life is the most precious thing to protect.
我十分为你感到骄傲
I'm very proud of you.
真... 真的吗
You... You are?
真的吗 不打屁股吗 不扇巴掌吗
Seriously? No spanking? No smack to the knuckles?
你就这样原谅她了
You forgive her, just like that?
当然啊 我们给予的大量的爱会支撑我们
Of course. We rise to the amount of love we're shown,
只有爱停止时 我们才会沉沦
and we sink only when that love stops.
汉库斯又哭哭了 又哭哭了
Hackus leaking again. Leaking again!
嘿 你找到了蓝妹妹
Hey, you found Smurfette!
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
哦 不 我们没有时间了
Oh, no, we don't have much time.
我们把配方找回来 然后赶紧逃 呼哈
Let's just get the formula back and get out of here. Hooah!
等等 他们怎么办
Wait! What about them?
他们怎么办 他们绑架了你
What about them? They kidnapped you.
对啊 他们是格格巫的人
Yeah, they're Gargamel's.
我也是 但爸爸从来没有放弃我
So was I, but Papa never gave up on me.
所以我也不会放弃他们的
So I'm not about to give up on them.
你还以为自己不是真正的蓝精灵呢
And you thought you weren't a real Smurf.
-救他们出来 快点  -好的 爸爸
-Get them out, quickly. -Right, Papa.
自由的汉库斯
Free Hackus!
这样一共有七只了 对吧
And then there were seven, eh?
你好啊 小猫咪
Hello, kitty.
欢迎来到我的宴会 蓝爸爸
Welcome to the party, Papa!
看看这些蓝精华
Look at all this essence.
我真喜欢看你们这个样子
I love your work. Really, all of you.
特别是 你们现在痛不欲生的惨状
In particular, your Blue Period.
我全身都扭曲了
My whole body is scrunching!
你够了 格格巫
That's enough, Gargamel.
你已经提取足够多了
You have enough.
是的 是的 但你知道 蓝爸爸 我想要比足够更多
Yes, yes, but you see, Papa, I want more than enough!
毕竟 我得给这个充电
After all, I have to be able to power this!
我叫她 拉旺达
I call her La Wanda.
懂了吧 因为这是根魔杖是吧
You get it? Because it's a wand.
所以我叫它拉 很好笑就是了
So I called it La... It's very funny.
你们现在是疼得要死
If you weren't in excruciating pain,
不然你们一定笑尿了好吗
you'd be laughing hysterically, believe me.
有了这些魔力 还有什么我做不了吗
Whatever will I do with all of this power?
好 够了
That's right.
我要统治全世界
I'm going to rule the entire world!
不
No.
对了 蓝爸爸
And, Papa,
跟你说下我的第一步行动哈
I want you to know that as my first official act,
我要建一个从你们蓝精灵村
I'm going to create a portal all the
一路传到我精灵吸收器这儿的传送门
way from Smurf Village right here to my Smurfalator,
这样你就又能和你的蓝精灵小伙伴们在一起了
so you get to be with all of your little smurfy friends.
一辈子在一起
Forever!
想得美 格格巫
I don't think so, Gargamel.
接着砸
Hit it again.
-让我来  -快啊
-Give it to me. -Hurry.
快啊 他都把魔杖掏出来了
Hurry, he's going for his wand.
-一棍子砸了算了  -我这么美怎么可以死啊
-Just break it already! -I'm too beautiful to die!
我去啊 用尖的那头啊
For the love of Smurf, use the pointy end!
不要吵我 打啊
Don't just stand there yelling at me! Attack!
好诶
Yes!
不要啊
Oh, no.
阿拉卡
Alaka...
汉库斯好爽
Hackus real boy.
人家又要节食了
Thrown to the curb again.
笨笨 小心
Careful, Clumsy!
-次次都来  -不好意思
-Every time! -Sorry.
真的假的啊
Really?
蓝精灵击掌
High fours!
大家没事吧
Is everyone all right?
所有蓝精灵都没事
All smurfy and accounted for.
-帕特里克  -爸爸
-Patrick! -Daddy!
-嘿  -嘿 格蕾丝
-Hey. -Hey, Grace!
嘿
Hey.
我们成功了
We did it!
格蕾丝
Grace!
蓝妹妹
Smurfette.
我想死你啦
I've missed you.
我很担心你啊
I was so worried about you.
格蕾丝 这位是维可西 我的妹妹
Grace, this is Vexy, my other sister.
嗯嗯 看来你也是我的妹妹啦
Well, I guess that makes you my sister, too.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
这就是幸福的感觉吗
Is this what happy feels like?
好啊 美女 我也很美的
Hello, pretty lady! I'm pretty, too!
这位是汉库斯 我弟弟
And this is Hackus, my brother.
汉库斯
Hackus!
汉库斯 他们是格蕾丝和帕特里克
Hackus, this is Grace and Patrick.
-你好啊  -这是... 你的孩子吗
-Hello! -And... Your baby?
他叫蓝蓝
This is Blue.
太棒了 格蕾丝
You did good, Grace.
他真的好漂亮
He's blue-tiful.
这个呢 这个呢
Who this? Who this?
他是维克多
That's Victor.
他是...
He's...
他是我爸爸
He's my dad.
以及蓝蓝的超赞爷爷
And Blue's pretty fantastic grandpa.
爹地和维克多
Daddy and Vicster!
好啦 我知道啦
Okay. I got it.
我真的很为你骄傲 帕特里克•温斯洛
I'm really proud of you, Patrick Winslow.
-道尔
Hyphhen-Doyle.
-蓝精灵
Hyphen-Smurf.
太棒了 太为你们自豪了
Yeah, guys! Smurf pound.
-靓靓  -太棒啦 太棒啦
-Vanity? -Great job! Great job!
-喜喜  -起开起开
-Positive? -Hey, get that thing out of here!
我才不鼓掌呢
I'm not pounding anything!
我叫厌厌 我有一肚子气要撒
I'm Grouchy, and I got a lot of pent-up anger to vent!
哇 舒服多了
Wow, that feels good.
我又回来啦
I'm back!
我也回来啦
And so am I!
太好了
Perfect.
你们大多数都知道 拉旺达
I think most of you know La Wanda...
-真晦气  -这个词非常的搞笑
-Unfortunately. -...which is a hilarious play on words.
-蓝妹妹  -见识下我的大家伙
-Smurfette. -Say hello to my enormous friend!
你想都别想 格格巫
I don't think so, Gargamel!
好啊
Yeah!
旺达 拉旺达 不要啊
Wanda! No, La Wanda, no!
这东西到底是要怎么关掉啊
Where is the "Off" Button on this thing?
不要啊啊啊啊
No,no,no,no.
不
No...
不要啊 拉旺达 不要就是不要啊
No, La Wanda! No means no!
这真是 会疼死人的啊
This is really, really gonna hurt.
-太棒了 蓝妹妹 太棒了  -干得漂亮 蓝妹妹
-Bravo, Smurfette! Bravo! -Good job, Smurfette!
太棒了
That was amazing!
呃 这样的话格格巫也就不闹腾了
Well, that takes care of Gargamel.
回家吧 各位
Let's go home, everybody!
-耶  -回家啦
-Yeah! -Home!
我们还有一个小问题
We still have one small problem.
我只剩五块晶石了
I've only got five crystals.
我说 一个也不能少
Well, I say no Smurf left behind.
哇 蓝妹妹
Wow, Smurfette.
这魔杖你还用的真顺手哈
You are pretty good with that wand.
貌似我天生就会这个
It's kind of in my blood.
还挺困扰我的
Which used to concern me.
但是一个伟大的圣人曾经告诉过我
But as someone wonderful once told me,
你来自哪里并不重要
it doesn't matter where you came from.
重要的是你想成为什么样的人
What matters is who you choose to be.
真不愧是我女儿
That's my girl.
你也是我们的好爸爸
And you're our papa.
谢谢你给了我们一个新的家
Thanks for giving us a new home.
一个全新的大家庭
And a new family.
你真是个优秀的蓝精灵 爸爸
You're a good Smurf, Papa.
你将来也会是的
You'll be a good one, too.
我也会想你们的 蓝精灵们
I'm gonna miss you, Smurfs.
也许你可以用他们的名字命名一款你的玉米狗啊
Maybe you can name a corn dog after them.
这才像话嘛 就用蓝玉米好了
Now you're talking. We could use blue corn.
蓝精灵热狗 好好吃啊
Smurf dogs, yum!
对吧
Yes!
大家路上小心啊
Well, safe travels, guys.
马上就要回去了
And smurf back soon.
再次感谢你们 温斯洛先生
Thank you once again, Master Winslow.
杜利特小姐
Miss Doolittle.
小蓝蓝
Little Blue.
维克多老爹
Papa Vicster.
-再见 温斯洛一家  -再见 蓝爸爸
-Goodbye, Winslow family. -Goodbye, Papa.
-再见  -回见哟
-Bye-bye! -Toodles!
-好啦 我们走吧 蓝精灵们  -再见 温斯洛一家子
-Well, let's go, Smurfs. -Bye-bye, Winslows.
我等不及回去见其他家人了
I can't wait to see the rest of my family.
再见 蓝精灵们
Bye, Smurfs!
-喂喂 保持距离  -不好意思啊
-Hey, personal space. -Sorry.
爸爸 你把蓝妹妹带回来啦
Papa, you got Smurfette!
欢迎回家 蓝妹妹
Welcome home, Smurfette!
-看这边  -是啊 我们回来啦
-Well, looky here! -Yeah, we're back!
-大家好  -太棒了
-Hi, guys! -This is good.
还给我们蓝精灵家族带回来了新成员
And some new Smurfs for our family.
各位 这是维可西
Everyone, this is Vexy.
-正点哦  -简直是超级辣妹
-Great goobaloo! -She's a sassy lassie.
嗨
Hi.
-你好  -我是贪贪啊
-Hi... -Hi, I'm Greedy.
你好吗 我是贪贪 想跟我一起吃一个纸杯蛋糕吗
Hi, I'm Greedy. You want to share a cupcake?
-哎呀  -这又是什么
-Crikey! -What the hey?
差点吓坏
I nearly smurfed myself.
汉库斯
Hackus.
汉库斯 他们都是你的新兄弟
Hackus, these are your new brothers.
我有新兄弟啦
I have new brothers!
抱抱
Squeeze!
等一会哈
Hold on a minute.
严格意义上讲
Technically speaking,
根据蓝精灵法典第六章
according to section six of
中的基因配对学理论来讲
the Smurf Code of Genealogical Legitimacy...
唉 直接踹他一脚得了
Hey. Just give him a punt.
-这个物种不可能是...  -汉库斯踹
-This creature cannot... -Hackus punt!
-真爽  -这孩子真有个性
-Yeah! -That kid's got style.
他是我们中的一份子
He's one of us.
经过漫长而又耐心的等待
And so, after waiting patiently to be relevant again,
我们伟大的念念终于回到他神圣的工作当中
our heroic Narrator steps back into his leading role
我们上回书说到
to point out that when last we met,
整个蓝精灵村忙着准备...
the entire village was busying itself with preparations for...
嘿 怎么这么多装饰啊
Hey, what's with all the decorations?
生日快乐 蓝妹妹
Happy birthday, Smurfette!
不好意思 让我先收个尾
Do you mind? I'm trying to bookend this.
-因此...  -嗨哟 踹他
-And so... -Yo, let's kick it.
...在这嘈杂的音乐粗鲁得将旁白淹没...
...as the music unceremoniously drowns out the narration...
献给我们的新家庭成员
This is for my new family.
Ooh La La by Britney Spears
耶
Yeah!
嘿 汉库斯 给你一件礼物
Hey, Hackus, I got you a present.
真好吃
Yummy!
耶
Yeah!
呼哈
Hooah!
旅途愉快
Have a nice trip!
啊啊啊啊 停下来啊
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no! Stop, stop!
救救我 旺达 救命啊 旺达
Help me, Wanda! Help, help me, Wanda!
你觉得你跑得了吗 过来吧你
And where do you think you're going? You are coming with me!
Live It Up by Owl City
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看
温馨提示: 最后还有剧情彩蛋
Magik 2.0 by Becky G ft. Austin Mahone
你有种再叫一遍试试 我又没玩脱
How dare you call me that? I have bungled nothing!
好吧 巴黎什么的就不要想了
Well, Paris is over, my friend.
又回到黑暗年代了 我们还是慢慢习惯下来吧
We're back here in the Dark Ages. I suggest you get used to it.
你要客房服务吗 对着窗户喊啊
You want room service? Why don't you yell out the window?
你倒会亮爪子了你
Don't you show your claws to me
不用就别亮 你个小娘们
unless you are prepared to use them, Mr Pussy Foot!
就是小娘们 小娘们 打我啊
Pussy foot! Pussy foot! Pussy foot!
不要啊 别打脸 打脸伤自尊
Stop it! Not the face! Not the face!
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看